<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7620</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21570</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/><NumberFormat/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="99.75"/><Column ss:Width="84.75"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="466.5"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="226.5"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_FORGOTTEN</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="14.4375"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Forgotten</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Zapomniani</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of the species/unit class</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESOLATE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Desolate</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Opuszczony</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="93"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESOLATE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“Once we dreamed of living forever. Now we hide in tombs of our own making. There is only one mind left in this dark place. It thrives on vengeance. It demands everything. I’ve nothing left to give. Our hatred twists and festers down here. The compound seethes with malice. Even the Drained are tainted by malice. They fight our enemies, but consume the Essence for themselves. They don’t share it with the commune. Our dream is lost. Will I become one of the Desolate when I am drained?”[br/]– Eldon Squawl, “RV-774584R: Recovered Heritor Logs.”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Kiedyś marzyliśmy o wiecznym życiu. Teraz kryjemy się w grobowcach, które sami zbudowaliśmy. W tym mrocznym miejscu pozostał tylko jeden umysł. Umysł ten żywi się zemstą. Domaga się wszystkiego. Mnie nie pozostało już nic. Nasza nienawiść wypacza i jątrzy tu wszystko. Cały kompleks aż kipi od złej woli. Nawet wyssani są nią skażeni. Oni walczą z naszymi nieprzyjaciółmi, ale esencję zużywają sami. Nie dzielą się nią ze wspólnotą. Nasze marzenie przepadło. Czy stanę się jednym z opuszczonych, gdy cała moja Esencja zostanie pochłonięta?”[br/]– Eldon Squawl, „RV-774584R: Odnalezione zapiski Dziedziców”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">GOLEM</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Golem </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Golem </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="108.75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">GOLEM</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“We thought it another decorative statue until a crimson jewel on its crest ignited and the lumbering form of an Es’Teq Golem moved to block our progress into the Heritor Vault sleep chambers. Even from a distance, the thing could drain the essence from our expeditionary forces, disregarding their body armor and shields. Slow but powerful, it pushed our advance back, sapping our lives and degrading our armor with its entropic blasts. We might still be fighting it today had we not deployed Reaper tech to counter it.”[br/]–  Counterstrike Captain, Stella Diamante, “RV-0511M: Records of the Purge”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Myśleliśmy, że to kolejny dekoracyjny posąg, ale wtem jego karmazynowy klejnot zajaśniał i golem Es’Tequ ruszył niezgrabnie, by zablokować nam drogę do komnat snu Krypty Dziedziców. Nawet z daleka był w stanie wysysać esencję z naszych oddziałów ekspedycyjnych – pancerze i osłony nie stanowiły żadnej przeszkody. Powoli, ale z wielką siłą odepchnął nasze natarcie, pochłaniając życie naszych ludzi i roztwarzając pancerze ciosami entropii. Gdybyśmy nie użyli technologii kosiarzy, zapewne nadal byśmy z nim walczyli”.[br/]– kapitan sił przeciwdziałania Stella Diamante, „RV-0511M: Zapiski o czystce”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">EATER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Eater of the Dead</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pożeracz umarłych</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="107.25"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">EATER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“I’ve only seen it once. Near the end of the Heritor Purge, this twisted construct called the Eater of the Dead rose from corrupted essence to consume the fallen on the battlefield. Many men were consumed outright. With each swallowed body, its strength and savagery increased. I confronted one of the fallen Heritor priests before he was consumed. Choking, he disgorged the words, ‘For Justice!’ then plunged into its hungry maw. Why is it, when men construct gods, they focus solely upon the Law of Justice, ignoring the Law of Mercy?”[br/]– Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-97009X: Running from Monsters"</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Widziałem to tylko raz. Pod koniec czystki Dziedziców ten szalony konstrukt nazywany pożeraczem umarłych uformował się ze skażonej esencji, by żywić się poległymi na polu bitwy. Wielu ludzi zostało pożartych natychmiast. Każde połknięte zwłoki zwiększały siłę i dzikość pożeracza. Przyjrzałem się jednemu z poległych kapłanów Dziedziców, zanim został pożarty. Dławiąc się, wykrztusił „Za sprawiedliwość”, a potem został wrzucony do głodnej paszczy pożeracza. Dlaczego zawsze jest tak, że gdy człowiek tworzy bogów, oni skupiają się tylko na sprawiedliwości, lekceważąc miłosierdzie?”[br/]– Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-97009X: Uciekając przed potworami"</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SHATTERED_ARK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Shattered Ark</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Zdruzgotana Arka</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105.75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SHATTERED_ARK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The Quintessence Ark of Heritor Vaults are valuable in the right hands (mine). I’ve sent many expeditions to remote worlds to retrieve these treasures. It does wonders for my skin tone. On one expedition, my Indentured absconded with the fragments of an Ark, only to discover that it was—for lack of a better description—haunted. This Corrupt Ark consumed the life of my servants and had lost its wholistic qualities. Since it seemed bent on revenge, I sent it to a rival. It had great effect. Have you seen her frown lines?”[br/]– Syndicate Beauty Operative, Adira Mulari, “RV-74738E: Cosmic Cosmetology”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Arka Kwintesencji z Krypt Dziedziców będzie bardzo cenna we właściwych rękach (to znaczy moich). Wysłałam już mnóstwo ekspedycji do odległych światów, by sprowadzać ich skarby. One bardzo dobrze robią mojej cerze. Podczas jednej z wypraw moi ofiarni uciekli z fragmentami Arki tylko po to, by dowiedzieć się, że jest ona – z braku lepszych słów – nawiedzona. Ta skażona Arka wchłonęła życie moich sług i utraciła swoje holistyczne właściwości. Posłałam ją jednej z moich rywalek, gdyż wydawała się zafiksowana na zemście. Plan zadziałał. Widzieliście jej zmarszczki?”[br/]Agentka estetyczna Syndykatu Adira Mulari, „RV-74738E: Kosmiczna kosmetologia”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SERPION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Serpion</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Serpion</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="108.75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SERPION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“In the Vault, my spy-bots observed a Serpion. It slithered between life pods, the living jewel on its crest pulsating. Upon discovering a cracked case, it plunged its fangs into the occupant, draining the body's essence, turning it into a lifeless husk. The creature's fins crackled with life, as it climbed up the hierarchy of dreaming bodies to a row of Heritor elite where it used its injecting tail to fill their decorative chambers with vitality. It repeated this task, transferring life from the least to the privileged until it spied my camera and spewed entropic rot.”[br/]– Stealth Specialist Doreen, “RV-838899R: Reconnaissance: Heritor Purge Initiative” 
</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„W krypcie moje szpiegoboty wykryły Serpiona. Pełzał pomiędzy kapsułami konserwacyjnymi, a jego żywy klejnot pulsował. Gdy odkrył pękniętą kapsułę, zatopił kły w jej nieszczęsnym lokatorze i wyssał z niego całą esencję, pozostawiając tylko zewłok. Jego płetwy zaiskrzyły się żywo, gdy awansował w hierarchii śniących ciał na poziom elity Dziedziców i wstrzyknął witalność za pomocą ogona, wypełniając dekoracyjne komnaty. Potem powtarzał swoje działania, przelewając życie z mniej godnych do uprzywilejowanych, aż spostrzegł moją kamerę i zionął entropiczną zgnilizną”.[br/]Specjalistka od tajnych działań Doreen, „RV-838899R: Zwiad – inicjatywa likwidacji Dziedziców”  </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Female</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>5</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>5</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>