<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>GeraldR</LastAuthor><LastSaved>2018-08-10T07:41:20Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7620</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21570</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:StyleID="s62" ss:DefaultColumnWidth="9" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="162.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="102"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="483"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="280.5"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_PSIONICA</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="4" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PSIONICA_NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Psionica</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Psjony</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of the wildlife race. Both Single and Plural.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LIQUID_TICK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Liquid Tick</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Płynny kleszcz</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LIQUID_TICK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“When I was a child, I had a friend I ignorantly thought was a lady bug. It was actually a tick. Later, I befriended an alien beetle larva. It destroyed everything I loved. My life became a cautionary tale. Still, I persisted, studying harder, learning more. Now, I’ve made the discovery of a lifetime: psionic-crystalline lifeforms I originally named Psionica Derekus. Turns out, it’s a deadly parasite. It just consumed my grad-students. I give up! I’m renaming it to what it is. Just a stupid Tick! I should’ve been an accountant.” – Dr. Derek Hampton, “RV-2990484X: Personal Memoirs: Why Xenomorphic-Entymology Sucks.”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Gdy byłem mały, miałem przyjaciela, którego w swojej ignorancji uważałem za biedronkę. Potem okazało się, że to kleszcz. Później zaprzyjaźniłem się z larwą kosmicznego żuka. Zniszczyła wszystko, co kochałem. Moje życie stało się opowieścią ku przestrodze. A jednak wytrwałem, uczyłem się gorliwiej, dowiadywałem więcej. Teraz dokonałem odkrycia, które uznałem za swoje największe osiągnięcie – psioniczno-krystaliczne organizmy żywe, które pierwotnie nazwałem Psionicus hamptoni. Okazuje się, że to śmiertelnie groźne pasożyty. Właśnie pożarły moich magistrantów. Poddaję się! Zmienię im nazwę na odpowiedniejszą – to po prostu durne kleszcze! Powinienem był zostać księgowym”. – dr Derek Hampton, „RV-2990484X: Pamiętnik – Dlaczego ksenoentomologia jest do bani”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">REMORA</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Remora</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Podnawka</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">REMORA</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“We should have killed the specimen when it was weak. This Remora ravenously hungers for us all. I’ve seen it latch onto the campus security forces, completely draining them of life, only to then watch as their husks explode into a Psionica Tick obedient to the Remora. We sought shelter, but it hurled deadly mind-battering crystals that wracked us with nightmarish regret and agony. I’m afraid that, when you find this record, our school will be nothing more than a ruin, and this whole compound will be overrun with psychic parasites.” – Sully Chesterfield, “RV-8435355M: Pangalactic Academy Journal Entries”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Trzeba było zabić tego osobnika, dopóki był słaby. Teraz podnawka żarłocznie ściga nas wszystkich. Widziałem, jak przysysa się do uniwersyteckich ochroniarzy, dosłownie wchłaniając ich siłę życiową. A wysuszone trupy eksplodują i wyłaniają się z nich kleszcze psjonów, posłuszne woli podnawki. Szukaliśmy schronienia, ale obrzuciła nas drobniutkimi, tumaniącymi umysł kryształami, które przyprawiły nas o koszmarny żal i ból. Obawiam się, że do czasu, gdy ktoś znajdzie te zapiski, nasza uczelnia zmieni się w ruiny, a cały kampus zostanie opanowany przez te psychiczne pasożyty”. – Sully Chesterfield, „RV-8435355M: National Pangalactic”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LEECH</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Leech</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Pijawka</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LEECH</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Foremen claim that native Kir’Ko hives are stirring up conflict with our mining operation. The bugs claim Cosmite deposits are the bodies of gods long dead. Like most corpses, creatures feed on the decomposing remains. Our crew tried to ignore their paranoid superstitions, but some have nightmares of pulsating creatures of crimson crystal tunneling into their minds. They say it’s some kind of psionic parasite, capable of latching onto a host and siphoning life. Executives assert it’s a Kir’Ko hoax, but miners still whisper of Psionica Leeches.” – Tawny Walden, “RV-3482966W: Cosmicom Mining, Personnel Health Assessment”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Sztygarzy twierdzą, że miejscowe roje Kir’Ko przeciwstawiają się naszym operacjom górniczym. Robale utrzymują, że złoża kosmitu są ciałami dawno zmarłych bogów. Tak jak w przypadku większości trupów, na rozkładających się szczątkach żerują różne stworzenia. Nasi ludzie starali się ignorować te paranoiczne przesądy, ale część zaczęła doświadczać koszmarów o pulsujących stworach z karmazynowych kryształów, które wwiercają się w ich mózgi. Mówią, że to jakiś pasożyt psioniczny, który może przyczepiać się do żywiciela i wysysać z niego życie. Kierownictwo uznało to za plotkę Kir’Ko, ale górnicy nadal szepczą o pijawkach psjonów”. – Tawny Walden, „RV-3482966W: Cosmicom Mining, Ocena zdrowia pracowników”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is a unit description. I.e. a bit of flavor text about the unit that gives an insight into the lore of the game. This takes the form of a quote - from a book, diary, journal, etc - followed by the source. A lot of them try to get across some of the humor Triumph is known for.

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>1</ActiveRow></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>