<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:55Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-06T09:39:56Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="144"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="143.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="428.25"/><Column ss:Index="5" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="192"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="86.4375"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_HOPPERHOUNDS</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER0</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Hopperhound Hatchling</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Larwa turkucia</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER0</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The hills are alive with the sound of nasty murder-bugs. ‘Tis the season to hunt hatchlings before they eat your pets and children. Join us. Slay the hopperhound young before they grow deadly enough to eat you.  Everyone grab a gun. You can’t slay them alone. They are deadly. They can leap and slash like any hopperhound. Meet at the Community Center on Bugsday Morning. Don’t forget the Bugsday Evening Feast and scrumptious Barbeque Bugs! Eat them before they eat you!”— Mayor Keat Hatyara, “RV-1943D: Bugsday Festival Announcement”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">„Wzgórza aż huczą od odgłosów wydawanych przez wredne, mordercze żuki. Mamy sezon polowań na larwy – trzeba je ubić, zanim pożrą ci zwierzaki domowe i dzieci. Dołącz do nas. Zabijaj młode turkucie, bo inaczej urosną tak bardzo, że zjedzą cię na śniadanie bez popitki. Niech każdy łapie za strzelbę. Nie dasz rady w pojedynkę. To zabójcze bestie. Potrafią skakać i ciąć pazurami jak każdy dorosły turkuć. Spotkamy się pod domem kultury rankiem pierwszego dnia festynu. Nie zapomnij też przyjść na Wieczorną Owadzią Wyżerkę i przepyszne żuki z grilla! Zjedz je, zanim one zjedzą ciebie!” – burmistrz Keat Hatyara, „RV-1943D – Rozpoczęcie Festynu Martwego Żuka”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: hopperound -&gt; hopperhound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Hopperhound Manhunter</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Turkuć człekożer</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“I remember the first year in Sundew Valley in the farming colony. The rich soil and favorable climate made life ideal for growing crops. Our community grew strong as we lived our happy lives one bounteous harvest after the next. We prospered for a decade spreading out over the valley until something wicked awoke in Hopper Hill. A Manhunter. Green and covered in spines, its legs were scythes, leaping across our fields. It cares nothing for our crops. It hungers for the men who cultivate the land. We are its crop.”— Patchery Mazz, “RV-6988D: The Surrender of Sundew Valley”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">„Pamiętam swój pierwszy rok w kolonii rolniczej Doliny Rosy. Żyzna gleba i łagodny klimat sprawiły, że ten teren idealnie nadaje się pod uprawę zbóż. Nasza społeczność rozrastała się, a my żyliśmy szczęśliwie, od jednych obfitych żniw do następnych. Przez całą dekadę niczego nam nie brakowało i zajmowaliśmy coraz większą część doliny. Aż na Wzgórzu Turkuci przebudziło się coś złowieszczego. Człekożer. Zielony, pokryty kolcami, o nogach jak kosy, zaczął nawiedzać nasze pola. Nie dbał o rosnące tam zboże – chodziło mu o ludzi, którzy uprawiali tę ziemię. To my jesteśmy jego żniwem”. – Patchery Mazz, „RV-6988D – Upadek Doliny Rosy”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Hopperhound Blademaw</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Turkuć trawieniec</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The bright red carapace clicked. It inched backwards against the cliff wall. It was the largest hopperhound we’d seen in generations. Long bloody slashes adorned the few remaining hunting dogs that brayed at it. The townsfolk closed in, raising their rifles for the kill. The first shot cracked the air, but the huge red hopper was already gone. It leapt over the dogs and encroaching villagers, striking a soldier. The man fell flat, dropping his weapon, as the creature's razor-sharp claws stabbed at him.”— Brian Froden, “RV-3480E: Hunting Bugs on the Frontier”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">„Jaskrawoczerwony pancerz zaklikał. Cofnął się o kilka cali w kierunku ściany urwiska. To był największy turkuć, jakiego widzieliśmy w ciągu wielu pokoleń. Kilka pozostałych psów myśliwskich, które go jeszcze oszczekiwały, poznaczonych było długimi krwawymi ranami. Mieszkańcy zbliżyli się, unosząc broń. Pierwszy strzał zahuczał w powietrzu, lecz wielki czerwony turkuć już przepadł. Przeskoczył otaczających go ludzi i psy, po czym zaatakował jednego z żołnierzy. Ten padł jak ścięty, upuszczając broń, gdy uderzyły go ostre niczym brzytwa szpony”. – Brian Froden, „RV-3480E – Eksterminacja robali na Pograniczu”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: as its -&gt; as the creature's</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Hopperhound Eviscerator</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Turkuć rzeźnik</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“If it wasn’t so murderous, I’d be excited about it. The hopperhound Eviscerator is the most aggressive carnivorous insectoid across the galaxy. This galactic infestation has intelligently hitchhiked onto vessels to nearly every colony the Star Union has touched. We originally thought hopperhound eggs were smuggled by rival malefactors to torment each other. My studies of the Eviscerator show it possesses predatory restraint sufficient to infest the galaxy using its own cleverness. Every time I encounter one, I can’t help but wonder if I’m staring at my death.”— Professor R. Lin’l “Bugman” Bunson, “RV-192S: Seti Alpha Outpost Recordings”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">„Gdyby nie był tak morderczy, nawet bym się nim zachwycił. Turkuć rzeźnik jest najbardziej agresywnym insektoidalnym mięsożercą w całej galaktyce. Ta pangalaktyczna zaraza w inteligentny sposób przedostała się do naszych pojazdów kosmicznych, by dotrzeć do niemal każdej kolonii, jaką kiedykolwiek kontrolował Związek Gwiezdny. Początkowo myśleliśmy, że jaja turkuci były przemycane przez rywalizujących ze sobą złoczyńców, którzy chcieli wzajemnie utrudnić sobie życie. Jednak moje badania rzeźnika wykazały, iż potrafi on pohamować swoje drapieżne instynkty wystarczająco, by rozprzestrzenić się po galaktyce za pomocą własnej przemyślności. Gdy spotykam jakiegoś rzeźnika, nie mogę się oprzeć myśli, że oto patrzę na swoją śmierć” – profesor R. Lin’l „Żukman” Bunson, „RV-192S – Rejestry posterunku Seti Alfa”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Hopperhound</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Turkuć</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LEADER_MOUNT_EMBER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Ember Hopperhound</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Rozżarzony turkuć</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LEADER_MOUNT_EMBER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Experimental Hopperhound created by the Star Union to serve as a weapon. Subdermal implants make it more resistant than normal specimens and a unique modification to their respiratory system gives them access to Thermal attacks.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Eksperymentalny turkuć stworzony jako broń przez Związek Gwiezdny. Wszczepy podskórne powodują, żer jest bardziej  odporny niż zwykłe okazy. Unikatowa modyfikacja jego systemu oddechowego umożliwia mu ataki zadające obrażenia cieplne.</Data></Cell></Row><Row><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>7</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>4</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>