<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:57Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-24T23:58:47Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7620</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21570</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:CharSet="1" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:Width="118.5"/><Column ss:Width="129.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="231" ss:Span="1"/><Column ss:Index="5" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="227.25"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="208.5"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="231" ss:Span="1"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_PSYNUMBRA</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ECHO_OF_DESPAIR</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Echo of Despair</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Echo rozpaczy</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="240"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ECHO_OF_DESPAIR</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">"There are many strange stories about the raid on the Psynumbra temple. Many men claim they were attacked by the embodiment of despair. I saw something—wisps of shadow that shook with nodding sorrow. I could feel the foreboding terror as they passed through the walls to steal our courage. One of them let out a dreadful shriek and exploded. Inky shadows splattered across my deputies. They clutched their heads and could scarcely string two intelligible words together thereafter. Why would anyone willingly join such a terrible organization?”—Sheriff Mack Willburgh, “RV-44006L: The Psynumbra Death Cult”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">„O najeździe na świątynię Psynumbra krąży sporo dziwnych opowieści. Wielu ocalałych twierdzi, że zostali zaatakowani przez wcielenie rozpaczy. Sam coś widziałem – kosmyki ciemności, które dygotały z przejmującym smutkiem. Gdy przenikały przez ściany, by wykraść nam odwagę, miałem przeczucie nadciągającego przestrachu. Jeden z nich wydał z siebie przerażający wrzask i wybuchł. Atramentowe cienie pochlapały moich funkcjonariuszy. Oni kurczowo złapali się za głowy, a potem ledwo byli w stanie sklecić dwa rozsądne słowa. Dlaczego ktokolwiek chciałby wstąpić do tak okropnej organizacji?” – szeryf Mack Willburgh, „RV-44006L – Kult śmierci Psynumbra”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">INITIATE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Initiate</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Nowicjusz</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="210"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">INITIATE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“It’s been my observation that, because true lasting happiness requires difficult sacrifices, many societies give up on it altogether. The Psynumbra have clearly decided not only to avoid happiness but to fight against anyone who tries to find it. No matter their race, Psynumbra Initiates stoke hatred and malevolence. Cold and dark, Initiates can rob victims of hope. They employ a psionic attack called a Soul Spear, which breaks the mind of an adversary. I try to avoid them. My friends already think I’m insane as I am.”—Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-22299X: Forlorn Fantasy Destinations”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">„Prawdziwe, trwałe szczęście wymaga trudnych poświęceń i zauważyłem, że wiele społeczności z powodu tej świadomości rezygnuje z jego osiągnięcia. Psynumbra niewątpliwie postanowiła nie tylko unikać szczęścia, ale i zwalczać każdego, kto do niego dąży. Niezależnie od gatunku nowicjusze Psynumbry podsycają nienawiść i złą wolę. Zimni i mroczni potrafią pozbawić swe ofiary wszelkiej nadziei. Stosują atak psioniczny o nazwie «włócznia duszy», który łamie wolę przeciwnika. Staram się ich unikać. Moi przyjaciele i tak już uważają, że jestem szalony” – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-22299X – Zapomniane fantastyczne miejsca”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">HERALD_OF_OBLIVION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Herald of Oblivion</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Zwiastun zapomnienia</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="255"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">HERALD_OF_OBLIVION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The Initiates bound my brother to a black stone slab. They chanted. One lifted a dagger. I gasped. A gloomy ethereal claw reached out from my brother’s chest. It plunged the dagger into his own chest. The Psynumbra followers continued chanting. The shadow claws pulled itself out of my brother’s sacrificed body. Streaks of blood marbled the shadowy Herald of Oblivion. It stared at me. For a moment, I saw my brother’s lost soul tumbling through an endless pit. Panic forced me to flee. They will kill me, but I must warn someone.”—Linda Carpenter, “RV-44002L: The Psynumbra Death Cult”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Nowicjusze przywiązali mojego brata do płyty z czarnego kamienia. Ktoś zaintonował śpiew. Ktoś inny uniósł sztylet. Gwałtownie wciągnęłam powietrze do płuc. Jakieś mroczne, eteryczne szpony wychynęły z piersi mojego brata i pociągnęła sztylet, wbijając jego ostrze w ciało. Wyznawcy Psynumbry nadal śpiewali. Kreślone cieniem szpony wydobyły się ze zwłok mojego złożonego w ofierze brata. Krew znaczyła strugami ponurą sylwetkę zwiastuna zapomnienia. A on wbił we mnie wzrok. Przez chwilę widziałam w wyobraźni utraconą duszę mojego brata spadającą w nieskończoną otchłań. Panika zmusiła mnie do ucieczki. Zabiją mnie, ale muszę kogoś ostrzec” – Linda Carpenter, „RV-44002L – Kult śmierci Psynumbra”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">MALICTOR</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Malictor</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">Nikczemnik</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="195"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">MALICTOR</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The realm of the mind is vast and swirling. With too many senses, a feeling mind is scattered and weak. Those who receive ritual annihilation can only be revived in the single-minded Great Darkness of malice. I tell you this to strip you down. Other sentiments will destroy you. Only then can you wield the Soul Seeking darkness and unlock the Lure of Darkness. Only when you are directed by unadulterated odium will the darkness bind your enemies with cords of despair.” —Murgle Fain, “RV-43092R: Psynumbra Ritual of the Malictor”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">„Królestwo umysłu jest rozległe i wzburzone. Czujący umysł, stymulowany zbyt dużą liczbą zmysłów, jest rozproszony i słaby. Ci, którzy doznają rytualnego unicestwienia, mogą zostać ożywieni jedynie w zdeterminowanej Wielkiej Ciemności zła. Mówię ci to, aby cię obnażyć. Inne uczucia cię zniszczą. Dopiero wtedy będziesz mógł władać tropiącą dusze ciemnością i uzyskać Powab Mroku. Dopiero wtedy, gdy będzie tobą kierować nieskażona nienawiść, ciemność spęta twych nieprzyjaciół więzami rozpaczy” – Murgle Fain, „RV-43092R – Rytuał nikczemnika Psynumbry”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">FLEETING_APPARITION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Whisper of Discord</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Szept niezgody</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="195"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">FLEETING_APPARITION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“There is something off about this place. The ruins of the Psynumbra headquarters still give me an unsettled feeling. The colony wants a security guard to make sure nobody enters and tries to dig up dirt on the place. Already two intruders were murdered under mysterious circumstances. The last guard quit after a week. But there’s nothing there, right? I want to fight myself just looking at the abandoned building. Sometimes I hear whispers. It’s enough to give a man the shivers.”— Night Watchman, Shaquawn Rhodes, “RV-345699E: Ghost Hunters”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„W tym miejscu jest coś niepokojącego. Ruiny kwatery głównej Psynumbra wciąż wywołują nerwowość. Kolonia chce, aby jakiś ochroniarz dbał o to, by nikt tu nie wchodził i nie próbował grzebać w tym miejscu. Już dwóch intruzów zamordowano w tajemniczych okolicznościach. Poprzedni stróż rzucił tę robotę po tygodniu. Ale tam nic nie ma, tak? Zmuszam się, żeby chociaż spojrzeć na ten opuszczony budynek. Czasem słyszę jakieś szepty. To wystarczy, by przyprawić człowieka o dreszcze”. – stróż nocny Shaquawn Rhodes, „RV-345699E – Łowcy duchów”</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><TopRowVisible>9</TopRowVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>12</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>3</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>