<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:55Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-06T09:39:55Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="14.4375"><Column ss:Width="105.75"/><Column ss:Width="84.75"/><Column ss:Width="238.5"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:Width="176.25"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="100.6875"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_THEGROWTH</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">WORKER_BEE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Worker Bee</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pszczoła robotnica</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="195"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">WORKER_BEE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“Worker Bees flitted from blossom to blossom, collecting nectar. We thought to steal some from the towering blossoms when we saw the swarm of vicious green Soldier Bees chase a hungry herd of goats across the meadow. Eric peeled back a flower petal, reaching for bright amber droplets. The sugary aroma forced me to smile. Suddenly he flew onto his backside. He groaned, holding a wound in his gut, coughing in a cloud of golden pollen. Hovering above him was a Worker Bee. We ran. Nectar wasn’t worth our lives.”— Telaron Prim, “RV-563E: Rustic Recollections”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Pszczoły robotnice latają z kwiatka na kwiatek, zbierając nektar. Mieliśmy nadzieję wykraść go nieco z wielkich kwiatów, gdy zauważyliśmy, jak rój jadowicie zielonych pszczół żołnierzy goni przez łąkę stado głodnych kóz. Eric zerwał płatek kwiatu i sięgnął po jasnobursztynowe krople. Słodki zapach sprawił, że się uśmiechnąłem. Nagle Eric upadł na plecy, jęcząc. Trzymał się za ranę w brzuchu i kaszlał w chmurze złotego pyłku. Nad nim unosiła się robotnica. Uciekliśmy. Nektar nie był wart naszego życia”. – Telaron Prim, „RV-563E – Wiejskie reminiscencje”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: pedal -&gt; petal</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SOLDIER_BEE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Soldier Bee</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pszczoła żołnierz</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="210"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SOLDIER_BEE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“I discovered the origin of Growth Bee species by studying their life-draining abilities. Soldier Bees destroy enemies of the Growth. They spit corrosives, and their powerful penetrating sting absorbs enemy tissue to heal the Soldier Bee. This is because Growth Soldier Bees are constructed the same way we build a drone; the Growth uses the natural parts of native fauna. The fauna consumes a part of the Growth which hijacks that life. The life sprouts tumors. The tumors grow into adult Soldiers equipped to protect the Growth.”— Professor R. Lin’l “Bugman” Bunson, “RV-133S: Seti Alpha Outpost Recordings”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Odkryłem pochodzenie pszczół Matecznika, badając ich zdolność do uśmiercania. Pszczoły żołnierze niszczą wrogów Matecznika. Plują żrącą substancją, a ich potężne użądlenia wchłaniają tkanki wrogów, co leczy samą pszczołę. Wynika to z tego, że żołnierzy Matecznika się tworzy. Tak samo, jak my budujemy drony, Matecznik wykorzystuje naturalne części rodzimej fauny. Fauna spożywa część struktury, która przejmuje jej życie, a z niego powstają guzy. Z guzów wykluwają się dorośli żołnierze, przygotowani do obrony Matecznika”. – profesor R. Lin’l „Żukman” Bunson, „RV-133S – Rejestry posterunku Seti Alfa”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: added comma after "corrosives"
Edit: constructed. The -&gt; constructed the
Edit: Tumors -&gt; tumors</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">VINE_NODE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Vine Bud</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pąk pnączy</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="165"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">VINE_NODE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“I am green. I am the vine and the bud. I collect the riches of the earth. I drink from crystal springs. I taste golden sunshine. My vines convey me over the waters and earth. When tempests tear at me, my roots penetrate the unmoving ground and I become as unmoving as the rocks. When eaters invade to consume my tender leaves, my vines bind them until I can absorb their nutrient rich forms. I am the vine and the bud. I am green.”— Green Sprout, “RV-934D: Conversations with The Growth</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Jestem zielenią. Jestem pnączem i kiełkiem. Zbieram skarby ziemi. Piję z krystalicznych źródeł. Smakuję złoty blask słońca. Moje łodygi przenoszą mnie ponad ziemią i wodą. Gdy rozrywają mnie burze, moje korzenie wnikają w nieruchomą glebę i staję się tak nieporuszony jak skała. Gdy roślinożercy przychodzą pożerać me delikatne liście, moje łodygi pętają ich, aż wchłonę z nich wszystkie substancje odżywcze. Jestem pnączem i kiełkiem. Jestem zielenią”. – Zielony Kiełek, „RV-934D – Rozmowy z Matecznikiem”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">VINE_SPROUT</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Vine Sprout</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pęd pnączy</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="180"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">VINE_SPROUT</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“The Growth’s vines flailed all around me, clinging to anything they struck. The frantic strands of the great green bud curled around my arms and legs, pinning me to ground. Vine sprouts sprung from the earth. I was so entangled I couldn’t move a muscle without triggering a reaction from the constricting vines. Prodding tendrils drilled into my sides and arms, sapping my strength. It wasn’t until the company incinerated the main bud that the vines slackened and I pulled free.”— Sergeant Max Becker, “RV-4314M: Operation Yardwork”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Pnącza Matecznika miotały się wokół mnie, przywierając do wszystkiego, na co się natknęły. Oszalałe łodygi wielkiego zielonego pąka owinęły się wokół moich ramion i nóg, przyszpilając mnie do ziemi. Kiełki pnączy wystrzeliły z gleby. Byłem tak ciasno spętany, że nie mogłem ruszyć ani jednym mięśniem bez wywołania reakcji duszących łodyg. Ostre wąsy wwierciły się w moje boki i ramiona, wysysając moją siłę. Dopiero gdy oddział spalił główny pęd, pnącza osłabły i zdołałem się uwolnić”. – sierżant Max Becker, „RV-4314M – Operacja «Odchwaszczanie»”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: it -&gt; they
Edit: removed last comma
Edit: Sargent -&gt; Sergeant</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">FLOWERING_NODE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Flowering Node </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Kwitnący węzeł </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="180"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">FLOWERING_NODE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“Mayor Yalts warned all of us to steer clear of the field behind the junkyard. But when I took a stroll by the junkyard, instead of garbage, I smelled something sweet and delicious. I confess that I love sweets. Just beyond I discovered a maze of hut-sized flowers. The air was full of intoxicating stardust, and I knew I never wanted to leave. I never would’ve had the Mayor not arrived with a gasmask and a blowtorch. I’m told he had to forcibly remove me from a tangled mess of vines.”— Bortly Blather, “RV-808D: Sweet is The Growth”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Major Yalts ostrzegał nas, byśmy trzymali się z dala od pól za śmietniskiem. Lecz gdy udałam się na przechadzkę, zamiast śmieci wyczułam tam coś słodkiego i smakowitego. Muszę wyznać, że uwielbiam słodycze. Nieco dalej odkryłam labirynt zarośnięty kwiatami wielkości małych domków. Powietrze było pełne odurzającego pyłu, a ja wiedziałam, że nigdy nie zechcę stąd odejść. I nigdy bym nie odeszła, gdyby nie pojawił się major w masce gazowej i z palnikiem w ręku. Powiedziano mi, że musiał mnie siłą wyrywać spośród splątanych pnączy”. – Bortly Blather, „RV-808D – Słodki jest Matecznik”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: added "that" after "confess"
Edit: in -&gt; with</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SEED_CLUSTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Seed Cluster</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Grono nasion</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SEED_CLUSTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“I don’t trust salad, especially if it talks to me, so I steer clear of the Growth. Unlike most plants, they fill the air with allergens even after forming seeds and I hate swollen sinuses. Once, I did see a Seed Cluster attempt to spread its seeds. The thing could throw seed-pods that exploded like a grenade, and shoot seeds like a machine gun. I suppose if someone is slain by one of its seeds, a decomposing corpse is a naturally fertile place for it to grow.”— Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-4008X: Vacation Hotspots”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Nie ufam sałacie, zwłaszcza gdy mnie zagaduje, więc trzymam się z dala od Matecznika. W przeciwieństwie do większości roślin Matecznik wypełnia powietrze alergenami nawet po wykształceniu nasion, a ja nie cierpię, jak mi puchną zatoki. Widziałem kiedyś, jak grono nasienne próbuje rozsiewać swoje nasiona. To coś potrafiło miotać całymi ich pękami, które wybuchały niczym granaty! Mogło też strzelać nasionami jak karabin maszynowy. Spodziewam się, że jeśli ktoś zostaje zabity przez jedno z nasion, rozkładający się trup jest żyznym miejscem na kiełkowanie”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-4008X – Atrakcyjne kierunki wakacyjne”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The Growth</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Matecznik</Data></Cell></Row><Row><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>4</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>3</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>