<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><Author>GameScribes4</Author><LastAuthor>GameScribes4</LastAuthor><Created>2020-10-08T00:05:05Z</Created><LastSaved>2020-02-10T11:57:59Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7365</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>24000</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:StyleID="s62" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="198"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="66.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="515.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="147.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="378.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="95.25"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="60"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENARIODEFINITIONS_DLC05CAMPAIGN</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MISSION_ORDER01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">An aspiring paladin is sent to the protection of a lost colony.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Ambitny paladyn zostaje wysłany do ochrony utraconej kolonii.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">For "Paladin" see the corresponding entry in the glossary.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 1, Stanza 13</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 1., strofa 13.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"Oathbound" is the name of the new race.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">I pledge myself, from now and forever, to the protection and needs of the weak and the poor. As a Paladin, I shall heed the wisdom of the Seers and beware the voices of greed and immodesty that will tempt me to put myself above others. I swear to use this battlesuit to sow order where the Star Union’s fall reaped chaos, and to capture peace where the Cataclysm liberated war. From this day on, I am an Oathbound.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Niniejszym przysięgam, teraz i na zawsze, działać zawsze ku ochronie i wsparciu biednych i słabych. Jako paladyn będę baczyć na mądrość Wieszczów i strzec się głosów chciwości i nieskromności, które będą kusić mnie do wynoszenia się ponad innych. Przysięgam używać tego pancerza do szerzenia porządku tam, gdzie upadek Związku Gwiezdnego wywołał chaos, i zaprowadzania pokoju tam, gdzie Kataklizm spowodował wojny. Od tego dnia staję się Nieugiętym.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="6"><Data ss:Type="String">Niniejszym przysięgam, teraz i na zawsze, działać zawsze ku ochronie i wsparciu biednych i słabych. Jako paladyn będę baczyć na mądrość Wieszczów i strzec się głosów chciwości i nieskromności, które będą kusić mnie do wynoszenia się ponad innych. Przysięgam używać tego pancerza do szerzenia porządku tam, gdzie upadek Związku Gwiezdnego wywołał chaos, i zaprowadzania pokoju tam, gdzie Kataklizm spowodował wojny. Od tego dnia staję się Nieugiętą.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 264, Stanza 7</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 264., strofa 7.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">After Equis Arrethorn’s heroic sacrifice on Atrium Alpha, the High Paladius and his Seers have started to look for a worthy soul to succeed Arrethorn in the Circle of Heroes. They announced a “Calling of Bravery”, a friendly strife where aspiring Paladins can compete to prove their virtue and courage. I am among the few chosen ones admitted to its final stage.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Po bohaterskiej ofierze equisa Arrethorna na Atrium Alfa Najwyższy Paladius i jego Wieszczowie zaczęli poszukiwać osoby godnej do przejęcia schedy po Arrethornie w Kręgu Bohaterów. Ogłosili „Zew męstwa”, przyjacielski turniej, w ramach którego ambitni paladyni mogą rywalizować w celu wykazania się cnotą i odwagą. Należę do nielicznego grona dopuszczonych do ostatniego etapu tego współzawodnictwa.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 292, Stanza 1</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 292., strofa 1.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The last round of the tournament takes me to the Equisat of Verdrice, a rural planet once engineered by the Star Union to become a hyper-fertilized farming center. Like my competitors sent to other planets, I have been asked to seek out our existing colonies on the Equisat of Verdrice, shield its citizens from all danger, and build up a flourishing enclave of peace and prosperity. An accompanying Seer will be my judge of honor.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Ostatnią rundę turnieju będę rozgrywać w Equisacie Verdrice, na rolniczej planecie przerobionej niegdyś przez Związek Gwiezdny w superżyzny ośrodek uprawowy. Podobnie jak w przypadku moich rywali, wysłanych na inne planety, moim zadaniem jest odszukanie istniejących kolonii w Equisacie Verdrice, chronienie ich mieszkańców przed wszelkim zagrożeniem i stworzenie kwitnącej enklawy pokoju i pomyślności. Towarzyszy mi jeden z Wieszczów jako sędzia honoru.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 297, Stanza 25</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 297., strofa 25.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="60"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Our transport is nearing the orbit of our destination. Even from up here we can see the vast patches of the fields once harvested by the Star Union. I don’t know yet what exact challenges will await me on the surface, but the citizens of the Equisat of Verdrice are now under my vowed protection.[br/][br/]On my honor, protect them I shall!</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Nasz transportowiec wchodzi na orbitę planety docelowej. Nawet z tej wysokości dostrzegamy rozległe połacie pól, uprawianych niegdyś przez rolników Związku Gwiezdnego. Nie wiem jeszcze, jakie wyzwania czekają mnie na powierzchni, ale obywatele Equisatu Verdrice są już pod moją ochroną.[br/][br/]I będę ich strzec, klnę się na mój honor!</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Equisat of Verdrice</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Equisat Verdrice</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_PLANETFALL_OBJECTIVE_01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">OBJECTIVES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Find and protect the Oathbound settlements</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Odszukaj i obejmij ochroną osady Nieugiętych</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 462, Stanza 8</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 462., strofa 8.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER01_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">While the Calling of Bravery has reached its sudden end, my journey as an Oathbound Paladin feels like it only began. Following the High Paladius’ orders, I shall travel to Archanon-8 and its vast archives of knowledge, where I will come before Oracle, given voice by the vestal Seers. It is my final test of courage, as it is said that the eye of Oracle can peer through the very soul of a mortal man.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zew męstwa dobiegł nagłego końca, lecz wydaje się, że moja podróż jako paladyna Nieugiętych dopiero się zaczyna. Zgodnie z rozkazami Najwyższego Paladiusa udam się na Archanona-8 z jego przepastnymi archiwami i tam stanę przed obliczem Wyroczni, której głosem są Wieszczki-westalki. To będzie ostateczna próba mojej odwagi, gdyż powiadają, że oko Wyroczni patrzy w samą duszę śmiertelnika.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MISSION_ORDER02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">At the Star Union’s fabled capital world a new era begins.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Na legendarnym świecie stołecznym Związku Gwiezdnego rozpoczyna się nowa era.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 465, Stanza 3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 465., strofa 3.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The wisdom of Oracle is unfathomable. Speaking to it has changed me, inspired me. All the Paladins in the Circle of Heroes know that it guides their actions. When the High Paladius called me out to renew my oath, my voice spoke in the name of them all. For while we are each individuals with different strengths and opinions, we meet in the Circle as equals, united by one noble ideal and duty.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Mądrość Wyroczni jest niezmierzona. Rozmowa z nią odmieniła mnie i zachęciła do działania. Wszyscy paladyni w Kręgu Bohaterów wiedzą, że to Wyrocznia kieruje ich czynami. Gdy Najwyższy Paladius wezwał mnie do odnowienia przysięgi, mój głos przemawiał w imieniu wszystkich. Albowiem choć jesteśmy odrębnymi osobami o różnych zaletach i przekonaniach, spotykamy się w Kręgu jako równi sobie, zjednoczeni szlachetnym ideałem i obowiązkiem.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 473, Stanza 8</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 473., strofa 8.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">All Paladins in the Circle of Heroes are committed to a secret mission: to find and recover the Grail Configurations. These relics from a forgotten civilization are said to bring peace and prosperity to the planets housing them, and have appeared in many decisive moments of Star Union history. With each Configuration we Oathbound secure, we come one step closer to making the universe a better and safer place for everyone.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wszyscy paladyni w Kręgu Bohaterów zajmują się pewnym tajnym zadaniem – poszukują i odzyskują idealne konfiguracje. Podobno te relikty zapomnianej cywilizacji przynoszą pokój i pomyślność planetom, na których się znajdują. Idealne konfiguracje pojawiały się w wielu decydujących chwilach historii Związku Gwiezdnego. Każda konfiguracja zdobyta przez Nieugiętych przybliża nas o krok do uczynienia wszechświata miejscem lepszym i bezpieczniejszym dla każdego.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 473, Stanza 9</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 473., strofa 9.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">But all of that is suddenly at risk. The Assembly have succeeded with their insane plan and wrested Union Prime from the Void. Now the old capital world has reappeared on the star charts, drawing in all the aspiring factions who want to lay claim on this symbol of power and human heritage. What is worse, the Assembly seem to know about the planet’s biggest secret: the Prime Grail Configuration!</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Lecz nagle wykonanie naszych zamiarów zostało zagrożone. Zgromadzenie zrealizowało swój szalony plan i wyrwało Jedność Jeden z Głębi. Dawna stolica znów pojawiła się na mapach gwiezdnych, przyciągając wszystkie ambitne frakcje, które chciałyby zdobyć ten symbol władzy i ludzkiego dziedzictwa. Co gorsza, Zgromadzenie zna największą tajemnicę tej planety – idealną konfigurację Jedności!</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Testimonial of an Oathbound - Day 495, Stanza 6</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadectwo Nieugiętych – dzień 495., strofa 6.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Along with Equis Weviere and Equis Denard, I have been chosen and sent to Union Prime. As we are approaching the fabled planet, it is glimmering in black and gold like the treasury of an ancient kingdom.[br/][br/]But we must not be fooled by this image and think of the dangers ahead: only if we claim the Prime Grail Configuration in time, the Assembly can still be stopped!</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Equis Weviere, equis Denard i ja zostaliśmy wybrani do niebezpiecznej misji – udajemy się na Jedność Jeden. Gdy zbliżamy się do tej legendarnej planety, lśni ona czarno i złociście niczym klejnot ze skarbca jakiegoś pradawnego królestwa.[br/][br/]Nie możemy jednak dać się zwieść temu widokowi – musimy myśleć o czekających nas zagrożeniach. Zdołamy powstrzymać Zgromadzenie tylko wtedy, gdy zdobędziemy idealną konfigurację Jedności na czas!</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Union Prime</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Jedność Jeden</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_PLANETFALL_OBJECTIVE_01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">OBJECTIVES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Find the Prime Grail Configuration</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Znajdź idealną konfigurację Jedności</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Chronlices of an Empire - Preliminary Chapters</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Kroniki Imperium – Wprowadzenie</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">No great power should go unchallenged. The duality of Emperor and CORE is what brought stability and prosperity to the Star Union, and so will my reign as Tholian II, backed up by the wisdom of Oracle and its Grail Configurations. When I ascend to the throne, the traditions and goals of the Oathbound and Paragon will merge into a new ideology that stimulates the elites without abandoning the broad base of its citizens.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Żadna wielka potęga nie powinna być pozbawiona wyzwań. Dwoistość cesarza i ŚWIAT-a zapewniała Związkowi Gwiezdnemu stabilność i powodzenie. Podobnie będzie z moim panowaniem pod imieniem Tholiana II, wspieranym przez mądrość Wyroczni i jej idealne konfiguracje. Gdy wstąpię na tron, tradycje i cele Nieugiętych i Wcielenia połączą się w jedną nową ideologię, zachęcającą elity do działania, a równocześnie pamiętającą o ogóle mieszkańców.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">No great power should go unchallenged. The duality of Emperor and CORE is what brought stability and prosperity to the Star Union, and so will my reign as Carminia II, backed up by the wisdom of Oracle and its Grail Configurations. When I ascend onto the throne, the traditions and goals of the Oathbound and Paragon will merge into a new ideology that stimulates the elites without abandoning the broad base of its citizens.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Żadna wielka potęga nie powinna być pozbawiona wyzwań. Dwoistość cesarza i ŚWIAT-a zapewniała Związkowi Gwiezdnemu stabilność i powodzenie. Podobnie będzie z moim panowaniem pod imieniem Carminii II, wspieranym przez mądrość Wyroczni i jej idealne konfiguracje. Gdy wstąpię na tron, tradycje i cele Nieugiętych i Wcielenia połączą się w jedną nową ideologię, zachęcającą elity do działania, a równocześnie pamiętającą o ogóle mieszkańców.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT_HIDDEN</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">??????????</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">??????????</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_DEBRIEFING_SOLE_EMPEROR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">From this day on, I shall be known as Tholian II, regent of the new Star Union. The combined strength of Paladins and Paragon will be my scepter, the Grail Configuration my crown. It is my destiny to extend my oath of protection to all citizens of the old and new races, and to avert the danger of Oracle becoming a second CORE to control humanity. This empire will be our own.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Od tego dnia będę znany jako Tholian II, regent nowego Związku Gwiezdnego. Moim berłem będzie połączona siła paladynów i Wcielenia, a moją koroną – idealna konfiguracja. Moim przeznaczeniem jest objąć przysięgą obrony wszystkich mieszkańców, pochodzących tak ze starych, jak i nowych gatunków, i zadbać o to, by Wyrocznia nie stała się drugim ŚWIAT-em kontrolującym ludzkość. To imperium będzie należeć tylko do nas.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">From this day on, I shall be known as Carminia II, regent of the new Star Union. The combined strength of Paladins and Paragon will be my scepter, the Grail Configuration my crown. It is my destiny to extend my oath of protection to all citizens of the old and new races, and to avert the danger of Oracle becoming a second CORE to control humanity. This empire will be our own.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Od tego dnia będę znana jako Carminia II, regentka nowego Związku Gwiezdnego. Moim berłem będzie połączona siła paladynów i Wcielenia, a moją koroną – idealna konfiguracja. Moim przeznaczeniem jest objąć przysięgą obrony wszystkich mieszkańców, pochodzących tak ze starych, jak i nowych gatunków, i zadbać o to, by Wyrocznia nie stała się drugim ŚWIAT-em kontrolującym ludzkość. To imperium będzie należeć tylko do nas.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ORDER02_DEBRIEFING_JOINED_ELOP</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Union Prime is the name, and a new union is what we shall build, here, on top of the ruined ambitions of the Paragon, Syndicate and Assembly. Together with the ELOP commanders we are devising an intergalactic senate with the recovered Grail Configuration at its center. It is the birth of a galactic empire where common values and cooperation pledge protection to all citizens, be they human, Kir’Ko or even Shakarn.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Jedność Jeden – tak będzie brzmieć nazwa nowego związku, który zbudujemy na ruinach ambicji Wcielenia, Syndykatu i Zgromadzenia. Wraz z dowódcami z ELP przygotowujemy galaktyczny senat, w którego centrum spocznie odzyskana idealna konfiguracja. Oto narodziny międzygwiezdnego imperium, w którym panują wspólne wartości i współpraca na rzecz ochrony wszystkich obywateli – czy to ludzi, czy Kir’Ko, czy nawet Szakarnów.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"ELOP" is the short form for "Egalitarian League of Planets" (see corresponding glossary entry).</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male or Female Oathbound</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">General Loca Notes for this XML: For references to game terminology and in-world references, please check the glossary delivered as part of the documentation.

In the text below, text is spoken by a character who can be either male or female (except for Amazon, which is always female). If relevant for translation, please use the ‘localized string’ column for the male text and the ‘alternative localized string’ column for the female text.</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Zoom>89</Zoom><Selected/><TopRowVisible>9</TopRowVisible><LeftColumnVisible>1</LeftColumnVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>30</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>5</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>