<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:58Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-24T23:56:50Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:CharSet="1" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:CharSet="1" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="14.4375"><Column ss:Width="84.75" ss:Span="1"/><Column ss:Index="3" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="301.5"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:Width="273"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="57.5625"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_SPACERS</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">PSYCHO</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Psycho</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Psychol</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="150"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">PSYCHO</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“Star Union citizens who survived did so at a tremendous cost to their sanity. While we slept in space, generations endured the collapse of society, constant starvation, cannibalism, the insanity of the ruptured Void, and poison in the earth and sky.  How could a man recover whole? The short answer: they don’t. Spacers call their kettle-headed infantry Psychos. They fight over the last useful scraps of tech—anything they can use to get an advantage. In a pinch, they can turn violently mad at the flick of a switch.”—Senior Sanxus Bellows, “RV-481M: Aftermath and Anarchy” </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Obywatele Związku Gwiezdnego, którzy przeżyli, musieli stawić czoła ogromnemu obciążeniu psychicznemu. Gdy my spaliśmy w przestrzeni kosmicznej, całe pokolenia doświadczyły rozpadu społeczeństwa, nieustannego głodu, kanibalizmu, szaleństwa rozdartej Pustki i trucizn na ziemi i niebie. Jak człowiek może się z tego otrząsnąć? Krótko mówiąc – nie może. Przestrzennicy nazywają tę piechotę o zniekształconych głowach psycholami. Walczą oni o ostatnie użyteczne resztki technologii – cokolwiek, co mogliby wykorzystać od uzyskania przewagi. W razie potrzeby potrafią wpaść w brutalny szał niczym za naciśnięciem guzika” – starszy Sanxus Bellows, „RV-481M – Pokłosie i anarchia” </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TRUCK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Truck</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Pick-up</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="165"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TRUCK</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“The Spacers were first to emerge from the forced peace created by the Star Union. When food was no longer treated to pacify people’s instincts, Spacer forefathers embraced their basest nature. They care nothing for aesthetics or civilization. Their only desires are the pleasure devices wherein they live out their cruel fantasies in virtual worlds. Without such devices, ironically, they become even more reckless. They’ll deliberately crash their trucks into enemies, laughing all the way. They think they’re in a shooting, driving game with or without their VR gaming gear.”—Anthropologist, Dr. Sarah Harkness, “RV-6012H: A Past of Twisted Purposes”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">„Przestrzennicy jako pierwsi wyłonili się z pokoju narzuconego przez Związek Gwiezdny. Gdy żywność przestała zawierać substancje uspokajające ludzkie instynkty, przodkowie Przestrzenników przyjęli w pełni swą najbardziej prymitywną naturę. Nie dbają o estetykę ani cywilizację. Pożądają jedynie urządzeń do zabawy, dzięki którym mogą przeżywać swoje okrutne fantazje w wirtualnej rzeczywistości. Jak na ironię, bez takich urządzeń stają się jeszcze bardziej lekkomyślni. Z rozmysłem posyłają swoje pick-upy na zderzenie z pojazdami wrogów, śmiejąc się maniakalnie. Są przekonani, że grają w jakąś brutalną grę, nawet gdy nie mają na głowie hełmów wprowadzających ich w wirtualną rzeczywistość” – dr antropologii Sarah Harkness, „RV-6012H – Pokrętne cele przeszłości”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">MELTER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Melter</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Chemik</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="150"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">MELTER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“We approached a Spacer colony cautiously. Commander said many Spacers lived off junkyards when civilization collapsed. I wondered how that could be healthy. Then I saw a Melter. He was larger than normal. His distorted face looked like melted candlewax. His body was covered in rolls of fat that repelled the acid sloshing in containers on his back. He grinned, pointing a barrel-sized chemical sprayer at our Armored Tank. The acid ate through its armor. We fled on foot as he lobbed cannisters of corrosive gas at our backs.”—Ensign Ryland Grubell, “RV-1274M: Personnel Journal Entries”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Ostrożnie zbliżyliśmy się do kolonii Przestrzenników. Komendant twierdził, że wielu z nich żyło na śmietniskach, gdy doszło do rozpadu cywilizacji. Zastanawiało mnie, czy to było zdrowe. A potem zobaczyłem chemika. Był większy od zwykłego człowieka. Jego zniekształcona twarz przypominała stopiony wosk. Ciało miał pokryte zwałami tłuszczu, które osłaniały go przed kwasem chlupoczącym w zbiornikach, jakie miał przytroczone do pleców. Wyszczerzył się, kierując na nasz czołg rozpylacz wielki niczym armata. Kwas przeżarł pancerz czołgu, więc musieliśmy uciekać pieszo, podczas gdy on obrzucał nas butlami ze żrącym gazem” – chorąży Ryland Grubell, „RV-1274M – Dziennik osobisty”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">HELLCOPTER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Hellcopter</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Piekłopter</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="165"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">HELLCOPTER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">"I awoke to a loud boom. I jumped from my bunk and dashed from the barracks. The glow of flames lit the bunker wall. In the air screamed a hovering junkpile. It catapulted a fiery barrel. Radiant flames engulfed the armory. I trained my rifle on it. My shots reflected harmlessly off the heavy armor plating. The flying ship turned. The air was a wash of fire. I jumped into a retaining pond as spurts of liquid flame roiled over where I was standing. I understood why they called it a Hellcopter.” [br/]—Captain Addria Alethra, “RV-4468M: Encounters”[br/]</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Przebudził mnie głośny huk. Wyskoczyłam ze swojej pryczy i wybiegłam z koszar. Blask płomieni oświetlał ścianę bunkra. W powietrzu unosił się wyjący stos rupieci. Wystrzelił płonącą beczkę. Świetliste płomienie ogarnęły zbrojownię. Wycelowałam w to swój karabin, ale kule odbijały się od ciężkiego pancerza, nie czyniąc mu szkody. Latający statek zawrócił. Powietrze stało się ognistą łaźnią, więc wskoczyłam do zbiornika retencyjnego, a miejsce, w którym przed chwilą stałam, zostało zalane strugami płynnego ognia. Teraz rozumiem, dlaczego nazywają to piekłopterem” [br/] – kapitan Addria Alethra, „RV-4468M – Spotkania”[br/]</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">JUNK_SHIP</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Junk Ship</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Śmieciara</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="165"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">JUNK_SHIP</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“Spacers travel the waters in what looks like a floating junk pile. The Junk Ship’s turrets shoot incendiary projectiles, and don’t be fooled by the rusted barrels that they launch at enemy ships. They are filled with an incendiary chemical that explodes with unquenchable fire. Away from their colony’s virtual debauchery simulators, Spacers become ferocious. If these cannibalistic savages can, they will act out their depraved fantasies on the sailors trapped onboard the vessels they board. My advice: Blow it up the moment you see it on the horizon.” —Lars ‘The Admiral’ Robinson, “RV-57682M: Restoring Order to the Sea”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Przestrzennicy przemierzają zbiorniki wodne w czymś, co wygląda jak pływający stos śmieci. Wieżyczki śmieciary strzelają pociskami zapalającymi. Nie dajcie się zmylić tym, że wrogie jednostki obrzucają jakimiś zardzewiałymi beczkami – są one wypełnione zapalającymi chemikaliami, które wybuchają nienasyconym płomieniem. Z dala od swoich kolonii i ich symulatorów wirtualnej rozpusty Przestrzennicy stają się brutalni. Jeśli ci zdziczali kanibale tylko zdołają, będą realizować swoje zdeprawowane fantazje kosztem marynarzy pojmanych na zdobytych statkach. Moja rada – rozwalić każdą śmieciarę, jaka tylko zamajaczy na horyzoncie” – Lars „Admirał” Robinson, „RV-57682M – Przywrócenie porządku na morzach”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">MAD_PREACHER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Mad Preacher</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Szalony kaznodzieja</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="165"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">MAD_PREACHER</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“A raving lunatic hologram hovered over a scrap-iron vehicle, bringing a crowd of Spacers. The image pointed at my Lieutenant. Madness swept over us. My psionic indicators buzzed a warning. The mad sermon was an attack. Before I could raise the alarm, the Spacers mobbed the Lieutenant. Foaming at the mouth, they ripped him apart. The Spacers planted the Lieutenant’s spine and skull to a pole that radiated mental fury. Inspired by their macabre creation and spurred on by the ramblings of their Mad preacher, the Spacers’ superhuman homicidal wrath amplified.”—Captain Ben Carter, “RV-5688M: Mutant Incident Reports.”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Nad pojazdem skleconym z żelaznego złomu, prowadzącego za sobą zgraję przestrzenników, unosił się wizerunek rozszalałego wariata. Hologram wskazał mojego porucznika. Poczuliśmy falę obłędu. Moje czujniki psioniczne zabrzęczały ostrzegawczo. To szalone kazanie było atakiem. Nim zdołałem wszcząć alarm, przestrzennicy opadli porucznika. Z pianą na ustach rozerwali go na strzępy. Czaszkę z kręgosłupem nadziali na pal emanujący wariacką furią. Nadludzki samobójczy szał wzmagał się, podsycony tym makabrycznym dziełem i bełkotem szalonego kaznodziei” – kapitan Ben Carter, „RV-5688M – Raporty dotyczące incydentów z mutantami”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">EFFIGY</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Effigy</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Kukła</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="135"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">EFFIGY</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">“I knew the skull on that post. He died trying to save his family. The Spacers see non-Spacers as resources. That skull gives them power. They tally their kills like life is a game. There is nothing so corrupted that they won’t try it. That skull on the post is a dare to whatever is decent in the world—to any gods that stands for what is decent—that Spacers do what they want. They are the embodiment of rebellion and an Effigy is how they see us.”—Nurse Rachel Greene, “RV-1806H: Observations of The Fallen”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Wiedziałam, czyja czaszka zatknięta jest na palu. Poległy próbował ocalić swoją rodzinę. Przestrzennicy postrzegają wszystkich innych jako surowiec. Ta czaszka daje im siłę. Szczycą się liczbą mordów, jakby życie było jakąś grą. Nic nie jest dla nich zbyt plugawe. Czaszka wbita na pal jest wyzwaniem rzuconym wszystkiemu, co w tym świecie przyzwoite – wszystkim bogom nauczającym, czym jest przyzwoitość. Ona pokazuje, że Przestrzennicy robią, co zechcą. Uważają się za wcielenie buntu, a kukła pokazuje, jak nas widzą” – sanitariuszka Rachel Greene, „RV-1806H – Obserwacje poległych”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Spacer</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Przestrzennicy</Data></Cell></Row><Row><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><TopRowVisible>3</TopRowVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>5</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>3</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>