<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:57Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-06T09:39:57Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:CharSet="1" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="14.4375"><Column ss:Width="82.5"/><Column ss:Width="84.75"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="225.75"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="222.75"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="86.4375"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_PIRATES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ROY2</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Roy-2</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Roy-2</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="225"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ROY2</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">“Crave a real man? Meet Roy-2. This fully configurable male incubot  fits your every fantasy. With the latest in machismo matrices, he can be your rugged cowboy or a listening soul, capable of doing housework, cooking, and foot massages.  He’ll take care of your many cats without killing them. He’ll listen to your problems for hours. Just inform Roy-2 what role he’s to play. Unlike the Roy-1 model, his neural synthesis pathways are bound so that he’ll faithfully obey your every wish without the danger of him developing artificial free-will sentience.”—Unknown, Adworxs Agency Archive, “RV-077A: Elysium Robotics Account”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Pragniesz prawdziwego mężczyzny? Poznaj Roya-2. Ten w pełni konfigurowalny męski inkubot zrealizuje każdą twoją fantazję. Wyposażony w najnowszą maczomatrycę może być twoim nieokrzesanym kowbojem albo bratnią duszą. Gotuje, wykonuje prace domowe i robi masaż stóp. Zajmie się gromadką twoich kotów bez uśmiercania ich. Całymi godzinami będzie wysłuchiwać twoich zwierzeń. Wystarczy, że powiesz mu, jaką rolę ma odgrywać. W przeciwieństwie do modelu Roy-1 ścieżki syntezy neuronalnej Roya-2 są zawężone tak, że będzie on wiernie wykonywać polecenia bez ryzyka wykształcenia sztucznej świadomości obdarzonej wolną wolą”. – anonim, archiwum agencji Adworxs, „RV-077A – Sprawozdanie dla Robotyki Elizjum”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">EMMA3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Emma-3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Emma-3</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="225"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">EMMA3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">“Tired of holograms? Why not let Emma-3 give you a try? This fully configurable female succubot will have you spellbound. Programmed in all the arts of seduction, including cooking, cleaning, interest in your sports teams, and other unmentionables. Emma-3 lives to serve without all the shaming and the judgmental stares from her friends—because she’s a robot, and has no other desire outside of serving you. Voted most seductive, 9 standard planetary cycles in a row, this model is sure to never tell you you’ve been naughty… unless you want her to.” —Unknown, Adworxs Agency Archive, “RV-078A: Elysium Robotics Account”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Masz dość hologramów? Wypróbuj Emmę-3. Ten w pełni konfigurowalny żeński sukubot oczaruje cię od pierwszej chwili. Jego oprogramowanie obejmuje sztuki uwodzenia, gotowania, sprzątania, interesowania się drużynami, którym kibicujesz, oraz mnóstwo innych, bardziej dyskretnych. Emma-3 istnieje po to, by ci służyć – bez tych zawstydzających i krytycznych spojrzeń jej przyjaciółek. Jest robotem i nie ma innych pragnień poza służeniem ci. Emma-3 przez 9 kolejnych standaryzowanych cykli zdobywała tytuł najbardziej uwodzicielskiego robota i na pewno nigdy cię nie skarci… chyba, że tego zapragniesz”. – anonim, archiwum agencji Adworxs, „RV-078A – Sprawozdanie dla Robotyki Elizjum”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">E:Bot</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">E:Bot</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>5</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>4</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>