<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:59Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-06T09:39:59Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/><NumberFormat/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="14.4375"><Column ss:Width="93"/><Column ss:Width="84.75"/><Column ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="466.5"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:Width="215.25"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="86.4375"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_VOIDTECH</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2A</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Phase Manipulator</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Manipulator</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2A</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“The laser seared off my right arm. I saw it there on the ground beside me. Unavoidable, imminent death gripped me. The angry mob rushed forward to finish me. Then I blinked. I felt a slight tug. My mind buzzed. Somehow, I was behind a defensive bulwark beside a Voidtech Phase Manipulator. It was as if time rewound. My arm was back where it belonged. Crackling blue energy burst from the device dispersing angry protestors. Rifle in my restored arm, I returned fire with renewed vigor; saved by this Voidtech invention.”—Peaceworker Jaya N’Kilpanni, “RV-4417M: Famine’s Era”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Promień lasera odciął mi prawe ramię. Widziałam je na ziemi obok mnie. W oczy zajrzało mi widmo nieuniknionej śmierci. Wściekły tłum runął naprzód, by dokończyć dzieła. Potem mrugnęłam. Poczułam lekkie szturchnięcie. Zabrzęczało mi w głowie. Jakimś cudem znalazłam się w bastionie obronnym obok manipulatora fazowego Voidtechu. Zupełnie jakby czas został przewinięty wstecz. Moje ramię było znów na swoim miejscu. Z urządzenia wystrzeliło trzeszczące błękitne wyładowanie, rozpraszając szalejących demonstrantów. Unosząc odzyskaną ręką karabin, odpowiedziałam ogniem z nowym wigorem – uratowana przez wynalazek Voidtechu” – Jaya N’Kilpanni, siły rozjemcze, „RV-4417M – Czas głodu”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="15"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2B</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Echo Walker</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Echo</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2B</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“Anyone can learn to fold alternate dimensional probabilities using the Echo Walker, if they have the right Voidtech. We suggest program directors prescreen soldiers using this technology for single-mindedness. There should be no personal conflicts hidden within their psyche. Indecisiveness is a killer when entangling probabilistic quantum-realities. Some original prototypes created hostile dimensional echoes. Their doppelgangers actually attacked the tech-users. No one wants to summon their evil twin from an alternate dimension, even if it has better facial hair. The two must share the same willingness to destroy the same enemy.” —Trainer Richter Gray, “RV-3414M: Void Echo Augmentation Tech”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Każdy może się nauczyć składania alternatywnych prawdopodobieństw wymiarowych za pomocą maszyny kroczącej «Echo», jeśli tylko ma odpowiedni Voidtech. Sugerujemy, aby dyrektorzy programów wykorzystywali tę technologię do kategoryzowania na wstępie żołnierzy pod kątem ich determinacji. W psychice żołnierza nie mogą się kryć żadne konflikty osobiste. Podczas splątywania probabilistycznych rzeczywistości kwantowych niepewność jest zabójcza. Niektóre prototypy tworzyły wrogie echa międzywymiarowe. Ich sobowtóry atakowały użytkowników tej technologii. Nikt nie chce przywołać swojego złego bliźniaka z alternatywnego wymiaru, nawet jeśli miałby on bardziej hipsterską brodę. Obie wersje musi cechować ta sama chęć zniszczenia tego samego wroga” – trener Richter Gray, „RV-3414M – Technologia wspomagania echa Pustki”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="15"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">Rift Generator</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">Generator rozszczepienia</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">“I tried to warn them. General Mustlebox’s last words were, “It’s just a rift, fly over it!” That’s when the large donut-shaped ship projected a pulsating dimensional rift into the center of the company. Gravity shifted sideways. Time skipped. Vehicles, men, aircraft phase-shifted in all directions. The General’s vehicle rematerialized in a stone wall. Being unable to breathe solid rock, he died. My turret was rendered out of phase with reality. Our shots had no effect, phasing through its targets. The upside was we were intangible as the VoidTech weapon decimated the colony’s defenses.”—Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-3498X: Dimensional Explorations”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Próbowałem ich ostrzec. Ostatnie słowa generała Mustleboksa brzmiały: «To tylko zwykła rozpadlina, przeleć nad nią!». I właśnie wtedy wielki statek w kształcie donuta wytworzył pulsujące rozszczepienie międzywymiarowe w samym środku kompanii. Grawitacja rozsunęła się na boki. Czas stanął w miejscu. Pojazdy, samoloty, ludzie - przefazowani na wszystkie strony. Pojazd generała zmaterializował się ponownie w kamiennym murze. Nie będąc w stanie oddychać kamieniem, Mustlebox umarł. Moja wieżyczka została wyrzucona z fazy rzeczywistości. Nasz ostrzał nie dawał żadnych efektów, gdyż pociski przelatywały między celami poza fazą. Miało to i swoją dobrą stronę – byliśmy całkowicie bezpieczni, gdy broń VoidTechu dziesiątkowała obrońców kolonii”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-3498X – Przygody międzywymiarowe”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"/></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Selected/><LeftColumnVisible>1</LeftColumnVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>17</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>2</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>