<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><Author>Arnout Sas</Author><LastAuthor>Arnout Sas</LastAuthor><Created>2019-10-11T09:00:32Z</Created><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7620</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21570</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:StyleID="s62" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="93.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="86.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="465.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="110.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="221.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="85.5"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_THERIANS</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Therians</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Terianie</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of the species/unit class</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HUNTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Prowler</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Łowca</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HUNTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Feel the Call of the Wild… Do you ever wish you could just howl at the moon? Join the Therian Prowlers. Come run with the pack. Maybe you’re submissive and want a strong pack leader? Maybe you’re an Alpha and will take the lead? You won’t know until you let our genetechs alter your physiology and you feel the Thrill of the Hunt. When you feel your claws sinking into the warm wet haunches of prey you hunted with your most trusted packmates. Only a Therian life truly sets you free.” – Fang Whitemane, “RV-94949C: The Law of the Pack”  </Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Poczuj zew krwi… Czy chciało ci się kiedyś wyć do księżyca? Przyłącz się do teriańskich łowców. Pobiegnij razem ze stadem. Może łatwo się podporządkowujesz i potrzebujesz silnego przywódcy? A może jesteś alfą i staniesz na czele? Nie dowiesz się, jeśli nie pozwolisz, by nasi gentechnicy zmodyfikowali twoją fizjologię. Nie dowiesz się, dopóki nie poczujesz dreszczyku łowów. Dopóki nie zatopisz pazurów w ciepłym miękkim ciele ofiary upolowanej w towarzystwie najbardziej zaufanych towarzyszy ze stada. Tylko życie Terianina naprawdę cię wyzwoli”. – Kiełstut Siwogrzyw, „RV-94949C: Prawo stada”  </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BOUNCER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Bouncer</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wykidajło</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BOUNCER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Ever partied with a Therian Bouncer? Sure, they’re fast. Those daring privateers aren’t to be messed with in a fight with their dual pistol tornado of bullet spray, but what a crazy night on the town! Party animals give new meaning to ‘bouncing off the walls’! My buddy Bonzai didn’t take kindly to thugs. Always causing barfights! Surrounded, she bounced out of a mob of brutes. I ended up restrained in nylo-cuffs explaining to the judge that the real troublemaker bounced out of the bar laughing all the way.” – Social Influencer, Gaston Beaver, “RV-99548E: Only the Best Parties”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Imprezowaliście kiedyś z teriańskim wykidajłą? Szybcy są. Lepiej z nimi nie zadzierać – dwa pistolety sypiące gradem kul zapewnią naprawdę szaloną noc! I te suchary w stylu »ten klub jest za mały dla nas dwóch«! Moja kumpela, Bonzai, nie lubi sebiksów. Zawsze wszczynają bójki w barach! Kiedy ją okrążyli, wykopała na ulicę całą bandę. I to oczywiście ja skończyłem na komisariacie, tłumacząc, że prawdziwy prowodyr już dawno pogonił za tymi ABS-ami, rycząc ze śmiechu”. – influencer Gaston Bóbr, „RV-99548E: Same najlepsze imprezy”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SHARPSHOOTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Sharpshooter</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Snajper</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SHARPSHOOTER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Jett lifted his rifle, leveling his scope at the boar. A crack shattered Jett’s rifle before he pulled the trigger. Splatter from a biochemical blast left us choking from debilitating infection. He writhed on the ground, screaming in agony. I dove for cover, thinking the thicket would break the next shot. Lifting my scope, I turned and saw him waggling a mocking claw back at me. The sly fox face of a Therian Sharpshooter grinned widely as I suddenly realized that while we were hunting wild pigs, he was hunting us.” – Edger Tink, “RV-99436E: Nature Channel: Big Game Hunting”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Jett uniósł strzelbę i wymierzył w dzika. Ale jej lufa pękła, zanim pociągnął za spust. Chlapnięcie jakiegoś biochemicznego paskudztwa sprawiło, że powaliła nas obezwładniająca infekcja. Jett zwinął się na ziemi, wrzeszcząc z bólu. Ja zanurkowałem w gąszcz, zanim padł następny strzał. Unosząc celownik do oka, obróciłem się i ujrzałem, jak teriański snajper kiwa na mnie szyderczo pazurem. Cwany lis wyszczerzył paszczę, a ja zrozumiałem, że podczas gdy my polowaliśmy na dziki, on polował na nas”. – Edger Tink, „RV-99436E: Kanał przyrodniczy – Łowy na grubego zwierza”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CHEMIST</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Chemist</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Chemik</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CHEMIST</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The squirrel face is innocent enough. They are kind to those inquiring about genomic enhancement. They respect kin, but assume things with their quickened minds flitting from salutations to insinuations.  I thought just to inquire, but the Chemist insisted I try his wares. Soon, I was throwing chemicals and poisons in all directions. Filling the air with noxious clouds that only Therians could pass through unscathed. I suppose I had little choice then, but to join the flock, gaggle, herd, or pack. I don’t know what squirrels call themselves in a group.” – Howard Duncan, “RV-74799B: Howard’s Big Furry Transformation.”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wiewiórcza gębunia jest wystarczająco niewinna. Oni są uprzejmi dla osób wypytujących o modyfikacje genetyczne. Szanują swoich krewniaków, ale reagują zbyt pochopnie, bo ich przyspieszone umysły przeskakują od pozdrowień do insynuacji w mgnieniu oka. Chciałem tylko zapytać, ale chemik od razu nalegał, abym wypróbował jego towar. Wkrótce potem rzucałem chemikalia i trucizny, gdzie popadło. Napełniłem powietrze gryzącym dymem, przez który tylko Terianie mogą przejść bez szwanku. Chyba nie miałem wielkiego wyboru, jak tylko przyłączyć się do stada, hordy, watahy, tabunu, roju. Czy jak tam nazywa się grupa wiewiórek”. – Howard Duncan, „RV-74799B: Wielka transformacja Howarda”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">APEX</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Apex</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Fechmistrz</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">APEX</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The Therians would never have organized as an order when the Cataclysm shook the Star Union without the fearsome blade-wielding power of the Apex. Well, that and a little coaxing from me. Moonlighting as mixmaster for FuzzerCon, I saw panic spreading among the genomic animal-hybrid community. I reminded the lion-men of their noble heritage using a holographic fog machine and a voice modulator. With inspiring roars and pride pheromones, they gathered their circle of life. Though why they subsequently chose a life of piracy—I swear, that’s not my fault.” – Mah Reg’Nib “RV-90004T: Dramatic Life Changes and Other Meddlings”
</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Po tym, jak Kataklizm wstrząsnął Związkiem Gwiezdnym, Terianie nie stworzyliby swojego porządku, gdyby nie kunszt szermierczy fechmistrza. I bez mojej delikatnej manipulacji. Dorabiając sobie jako didżej na FuzzerConie, widziałem raz, jak w społeczności hybryd odzwierzęcych szerzy się panika. Za pomocą projektora holograficznego i modulatora głosu przypomniałem lwoludziom o ich szlachetnym dziedzictwie. Dzięki zachęcającym rykom i feromonom stada zebrali się w sobie. Ale że później postanowili zostać piratami, to nie moja wina, przysięgam”. – Mah Reg’Nib „RV-90004T: Drastyczne decyzje życiowe i inne interwencje” </Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PROTO_SQUIRREL</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Proto-Squirrel</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Protowiewiórka</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">This is the name of a unit.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PROTO_SQUIRREL</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The squirrel face is innocent enough. They are kind to those inquiring about genomic enhancement. They respect kin, but assume things with their quickened minds flitting from salutations to insinuations.  I thought just to inquire, but the Chemist insisted I try his wares. Soon, I was throwing chemicals and poisons in all directions. Filling the air with noxious clouds that only Therians could pass through unscathed. I suppose I had little choice then, but to join the flock, gaggle, herd, or pack. I don’t know what squirrels call themselves in a group.” – Howard Duncan, “RV-74799B: Howard’s Big Furry Transformation.”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wiewiórcza gębunia jest wystarczająco niewinna. Oni są uprzejmi dla osób wypytujących o modyfikacje genetyczne. Szanują swoich krewniaków, ale reagują zbyt pochopnie, bo ich przyspieszone umysły przeskakują od pozdrowień do insynuacji w mgnieniu oka. Chciałem tylko zapytać, ale chemik od razu nalegał, abym wypróbował jego towar. Wkrótce potem rzucałem chemikalia i trucizny, gdzie popadło. Napełniłem powietrze gryzącym dymem, przez który tylko Terianie mogą przejść bez szwanku. Chyba nie miałem wielkiego wyboru, jak tylko przyłączyć się do stada, hordy, watahy, tabunu, roju. Czy jak tam nazywa się grupa wiewiórek”. – Howard Duncan, „RV-74799B: Wielka transformacja Howarda”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Male</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><TopRowVisible>6</TopRowVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>13</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>4</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>