<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Glenn Smits</LastAuthor><LastSaved>2020-07-01T14:04:29Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7305</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21420</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62" ss:Name="Hyperlink"><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#0066CC" ss:Underline="Single"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s65" ss:Parent="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/><Interior/></Style><Style ss:ID="s67"><NumberFormat ss:Format="Scientific"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s68"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000" ss:Italic="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:StyleID="s63" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="108.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="104.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="409.5"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="173.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="85.5"/><Column ss:StyleID="s63" ss:Width="409.5"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_OATHBOUND</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Oathbound</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Nieugięci</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Race name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_PLURAL</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Oathbound</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Nieugięci</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Race name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="135"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s65" ss:HRef=""><Data ss:Type="String">{XML_SPECIES_OATHBOUND@RACE@DESCRIPTION_SHORT}[br/][br/][bulletList][bullet][sand]Starting Bonus: [/sand]Extra terrain revealed near starting colony[/bullet][bullet][sand]Long-Term Bonus: [/sand]Positive Reputation Modifiers last 50% longer.[/bullet][bullet]Battlesuits use [hyperlink,0000039E0000000D]Arc[/hyperlink] based melee attacks[/bullet][bullet]Seers manipulate probability to control the battlefield.[/bullet][bullet]Use the [hyperlink,0000039E0000000D]Arc[/hyperlink] and  [hyperlink,000003E900000096]Entropy[/hyperlink] damage channels.[/bullet][bullet]Racial Ability: Oathbound heroes can link to colonies for economic bonuses.[/bullet][/bulletList]</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">{XML_SPECIES_OATHBOUND@RACE@DESCRIPTION_SHORT}[br/][br/][bulletList][bullet][sand]Premia początkowa –[/sand] wokół pierwszej kolonii odsłaniany jest dodatkowy teren.[/bullet][bullet][sand]Premia długoterminowa –[/sand] dodatnie modyfikatory reputacji trwają o 50% dłużej.[/bullet][bullet]Pancerze bojowe wykonują ataki wręcz oparte na [hyperlink,0000039E0000000D]elektryczności[/hyperlink].[/bullet][bullet]Wieszczowie manipulują prawdopodobieństwem, by wpływać na sytuację na polu bitwy.[/bullet][bullet]Wykorzystują kanały obrażeń [hyperlink,0000039E0000000D]elektrycznych[/hyperlink] i [hyperlink,000003E900000096]entropicznych[/hyperlink].[/bullet][bullet]Umiejętność cywilizacyjna – bohaterowie Nieugięci mogą łączyć się z koloniami, zapewniając premie gospodarcze.[/bullet][/bulletList]</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s67"/><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The {text} inserts the DESCRIPTION_SHORT text below.
Racial description text</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s68"><Data ss:Type="String">All placeholder!! Copy of shakarn. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="Default"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="45"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION_SHORT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The [hyperlink,000003F600000318]Oathbound[/hyperlink] are a feudal society led by the wise Seers and their predictions of the future, guiding the honor-bound Paladins in their powerful battle suits to maintain order.[br/]</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">[hyperlink,000003F600000318]Nieugięci[/hyperlink] są feudalnym społeczeństwem kierowanym przez mądrych Wieszczów i Wieszczki. Ich przepowiednie prowadzą dbających o porządek honorowych paladynów w potężnych pancerzach bojowych.[br/]</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Short race description</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CAMP</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Oathbound Settlement</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obóz Nieugiętych</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Strategic map structure name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CAMP</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">A settlement is a small independent colony that might join you if you have enough influence.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obóz jest małą kolonią niezależną, która może przyłączyć się do ciebie, gdy będziesz mieć wystarczające wpływy.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Strategic map structure description</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MIGRATE_OPERATION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Migrate Colony: Oathbound</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Migracja kolonialna – Nieugięci</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Strategic structure operation</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MIGRATE_OPERATION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Migrate the population of this colony to Oathbound. The colony will become an Oathbound colony.[br/][br/][fireCol]By migrating the population, {PopulationDeath} of the colonists of the colony will be killed.[/fireCol] [br/][br/]You receive:[br/][fireCol]{Reputation} Reputation[br/]{RaceRelation} Race Relation with the {STR_raceName}[/fireCol]</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zmienia populację tej kolonii na Nieugiętych. Kolonia stanie się kolonią Nieugiętych.[br/][br/][fireCol]Migracja spowoduje śmierć {PopulationDeath} mieszkańców kolonii.[/fireCol] [br/][br/]Otrzymasz:[br/][fireCol]{Reputation} do reputacji[br/]{RaceRelation} do stosunków cywilizacyjnych z usuwaną cywilizacją ({STR_raceName})[/fireCol]</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Strategic structure operation description</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MIGRATE_OPERATION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">IN_PROGRESS</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Colony is currently being migrated to an Oathbound population. Process will complete in [INT_duration].</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Populacja kolonii jest aktualnie zmieniana na Nieugiętych. Proces zakończy się za [INT_duration].</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Strategic structure operation description in progress</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MIGRATE_OPERATION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CONFIRMATION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Are you sure you want to migrate this colony to an Oathbound colony?</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Czy na pewno chcesz zmienić tę kolonię w kolonię Nieugiętych?</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Warning tooltip</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LONG_TERM_BONUS</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WAR_PER_PLAYER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">At War (Player)</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Toczy wojnę (z graczem)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LONG_TERM_BONUS</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WAR_PER_NPC</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">At War (NPC Faction)</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Toczy wojnę (z frakcją niezależną)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCRYER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Scryer</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wróżka</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCRYER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Normally, I distrust powerful organizations. Absolute power corrupts. But what if the Oathbound discovered the perfect technology for a perfect society? I was wary of the Scryers hovering around our homes, but then it warned me when I was using a meat-grinder. It flashed a vision of me turning my hand into sausage, because I assembled the safety guard improperly. It’s stuff like that. They warn me about danger before it happens. What oppressive society cares so much for its lowliest citizens enough to protect them from their own stupidity? The Oathbound are alright by me.” – Beaver McSnubbins, “RV-93824C: Testimonials”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Zazwyczaj nie ufam potężnym organizacjom. Władza absolutna korumpuje. Ale co, jeśli Nieugięci odkryli idealną technologię dla idealnego społeczeństwa? Z nieufnością patrzyłem na wróżki latające nad naszymi domami, ale kiedyś jedna z nich ostrzegła mnie, gdy miałem użyć maszynki do mięsa. Przekazała mi wizję mojej ręki przerobionej na mielonkę, ponieważ źle założyłem osłonę maszynki. Takie buty! One ostrzegają przed niebezpieczeństwem, zanim wydarzy się nieszczęście. Jaki opresyjny rząd dba o swoich nawet najmniej ważnych obywateli do tego stopnia, by chronić ich przed ich własną głupotą? Jak dla mnie, Nieugięci są w porządku”. – Beaver McSnubbins, „RV-93824C: Świadectwa”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_ASPIRANT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Aspirant</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Aspirant</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_ASPIRANT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Lots of us Vanguard turned to the Oathbound. Pay is the same, but citizens respect you. I don’t police people, I serve them. We neutralize local hostiles, but even the lethal tech stuns first. Advancement is trust-based, rather than a race for who can hoard enough power to take control. Those caught abusing power either leave or are demoted to Aspirant to relearn a Paladin’s core mission: Service before Self. I am myself protecting the innocent instead of kissing up to high-ranking whack-jobs that want me to prove my loyalty by abusing vulnerable populations.” – Walter Jones, “RV-246014M: Recruitment”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wiele osób z Awangardy przeszło do Nieugiętych. Płacą tyle samo, ale na dodatek mieszkańcy cię szanują. Nie pilnuję ludzi, tylko im służę. Likwidujemy miejscowe wrogie siły, ale nawet śmiercionośna technologia zaczyna od ogłuszania. Postęp jest oparty na zaufaniu, a nie na tym, że jakaś cywilizacja zyska na tyle dużą potęgę, by wszystko narzucać. Kto nadużywa władzy, albo opuszcza szeregi, albo jest degradowany do stopnia aspiranta, by przyswoić sobie ponownie podstawową zasadę paladynów – najpierw służba, potem ja. Mogę chronić niewinnych zamiast całować tyłki wysokim szarżom, które chciały, bym dowodził swojej wierności przez wykorzystywanie słabszej populacji”. – Walter Jones, „RV-246014M: Werbunek”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WATCHER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Watcher</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Świadek</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WATCHER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Imagine if we could harness these Seers' ability to predict fate. Clearly, it’s tech, not magic—though they want you to think that. This is all that stands between us and galactic dominance. Yet how can you steal from one that sees what you’re going to do before you do it? Even their low-level Watchers see our weaknesses—always learning—constantly recording our attempts at espionage. Then they hit us with their ‘Curse of Adversity’, and then they observe as our plots fall apart on their own.” – Lady Kay of Syndicate House Tee, “RV-347223: Fate and Destiny”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wyobraźcie sobie, co by było, gdybyśmy mogli wykorzystać umiejętności Wieszczów do przepowiadania przyszłości. Oczywiście jest to technologia, choć oni by chcieli, żebyście wierzyli, że to magia. To wszystko, co odgradza nas od zdobycia władzy nad galaktyką. Ale jak można coś wykraść komuś, kto widzi, co zamierzasz, jeszcze zanim to zrobisz? Nawet świadkowie niskiego poziomu dostrzegają nasze słabości, ciągle się uczą i nieustannie rejestrują nasze próby szpiegowania. Potem rzucają na nas tę swoją „klątwę przeciwności”, a potem patrzą, jak nasze knowania same spełzają na niczym”. – Lady Kay z rodu Tee Syndykatu, „RV-347223: Los i przeznaczenie”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_PROTECTOR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Protector</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-obrońca</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_PROTECTOR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“We endured Spacer savagery for decades. En masse, they’d descend from their gaming arena for a ritual they called ‘the Munchies.’ Their hedonistic barbeque consumed our family members who couldn’t flee in what they demanded as gruesome tributes. We had no one to protect us until the Oathbound Protectors arrived. Brave souls fought with lightning lances, bearing shields that sheltered us all. The Spacers brought out their terrible constructs, but it only emboldened our defenders to fight harder. We are no longer bothered by Spacers. The Oathbound brought us peace.” – Quarla Arx, “RV-9444490T: Deliverance”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Przez wiele dekad musieliśmy znosić dzikość Przestrzenników. Wysypywali się całą masą ze swej areny gier, by urządzić rytuał, który nazywali „Pałaszerią”. Ich hedonistyczny grill kosztował życie wielu członków naszych rodzin, którzy nie zdążyli uciec i zostali porwani jako straszliwe ofiary. Aż do przybycia obrońców z Nieugiętych nie mieliśmy nikogo, kto by nas chronił. Ci mężni ludzie walczyli elektrycznymi lancami i nosili tarcze, które osłaniały nas wszystkich. Przestrzennicy sprowadzili swoje okropne konstrukty, ale to tylko zachęciło naszych obrońców do bardziej zaciekłej walki. Potem Przestrzennicy przestali nas niepokoić. Nieugięci zapewnili nam pokój”. – Quarla Arx, „RV-9444490T: Wybawienie”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description
Oathbound and Spacers are an in-game faction

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_WARDEN</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Warden</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-strażnik</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_WARDEN</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Like a congregation of true believers, we are strongest together, united in our common cause. I admire the strength in us all. Today, I serve as a Warden. When I draw back my bow, I deliver lightning darts to my enemies that hide in the sky or snipe us from afar. When the enemy surrounds us, I erect my banner and thwart their assault no matter how they try to outflank us. Should I falter, I may again become an Aspirant. Be it as the Seers foresee. No matter how lowly, I am forever Oathbound.”—Warden Ullen Strig, “RV-030422V: Solemn Devotions”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Jako grupa prawdziwych wiernych jesteśmy silniejsi, zjednoczeni wspólną sprawą. Podziwiam tę siłę, która tkwi w nas wszystkich. Dziś służę jako strażnik. Gdy naciągam cięciwę swego łuku, rażę piorunami wrogów ukrywających się w otchłani nieba lub ostrzeliwujących nas z oddali. Gdy nieprzyjaciele nas otaczają, wznoszę swój sztandar i odpieram ich szturm, niezależnie od tego, jak mocno próbują nas oskrzydlić. Jeśli zawiodę, niech zostanę na powrót aspirantką. Niech stanie się tak, jak przepowiedzą Wieszczowie. Nieważne, jak niską mam rangę, pozostaję w szeregach Nieugiętych”. – strażniczka Ullen Strig, „RV-030422V: Uroczyste nabożeństwa”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description
Aspirant is a unit as well

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">AUGUR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Augur</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Augur</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">AUGUR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“There’s finality to the universe. Fate. No one is so important that they cannot fall. Once you mattered, then you return to matter. We, the Augurs, are scarecrows posted on Fate’s crossroad. Feathery finality flurries like a flock of entropic birds, swirling with possibility. We reach out a hand. We don’t change Fate. We provide the raven of doom a place to perch and then we wait. Waiting. That is when we are most vulnerable. The Augur holds until Doom perches. One may soar, another will fall.” – Cortex Chambo,  “Training Seers and Soothsayers”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wszechświat cechuje skończoność. Przeznaczenie. Nikt nie jest aż tak ważny, by nie mógł upaść. Najpierw jesteś ważny, a potem zostaje z ciebie tylko masa. My, augurowie, jesteśmy strachami na wróble stojącymi na rozstajach Losu. Opierzona skończoność kłębi się niczym stado entropicznego ptactwa, wirując wśród możliwości. Wyciągamy dłoń. Nie zmieniamy Losu, ale dajemy krukowi zagłady grzędę, na której może przysiąść. A potem czekamy. Czekanie. To właśnie wtedy jesteśmy najsłabsi. Augur trwa w bez ruchu, dopóki zagłada spoczywa na jego dłoni. Czasem zerwie się w powietrze, czasem spadnie na ziemię”. – Cortex Chambo, „Szkolenie wieszczów i jasnowidzów”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">GALLEON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Galleon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Galeon</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">GALLEON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The ship cut the water like a swan, its bow and keel extended high and graceful. As it passed we could hear it hum and smell the distinct wafting of ozone as it pulled pulsating energy from the air. The marauding ships scattered as arcs of blue lightning snapped from the galleon’s Volt Bow. The ship was like a storm itself, and none of the vessels dared weather it. We salute these newcomers—these Oathbound. They do not allow injustice to persist—not even on the lonely seas.” – Captain Marshal Brightwater, “RV-577753C: Nautical Wisdom”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Okręt sunął po wodzie niczym łabędź, jego dziób i rufa wznosiły się wysoko, pełne gracji. Gdy nas mijał, zasysając energię z powietrza, usłyszałem szum jego maszyn i poczułem wyraźną woń ozonu. Jednostki maruderów rozproszyły się, gdy z elektrycznego łuku galeonu wytrysnęły smugi błękitnego światła. Galeon był niczym sama burza i żaden z okrętów przeciwnika nie odważył się stawić mu czoła. Oddaliśmy salut nowym przybyszom – Nieugiętym. Oni nie pozwalają trwać niesprawiedliwości, nawet na pełnym morzu”. – kapitan Marshal Brightwater, „RV-577753C: Żeglarska mądrość”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_CHAMPION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Champion</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-czempion</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_CHAMPION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“As our defenses broke and the bedraggled Oathbound faithful teetered on the edge of their resolve. A champion appeared wreathed in lightning, drawing arcs that crackled over us, pulling every hair to attention like a magnet. We cried out as it plummeted from the sky delivering decisive judgement with every swing of its Volt Greatsword. Every person that day who stood to fight for our noble cause vowed one day to be worthy to serve the people as a Champion and deliver the righteous will of justice.” – Danika Blaze, Paladin Champion Pilot, “RV-475888M: Why We Serve.”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Gdy nasze umocnienia padły i przemoknięci wierni Nieugiętych zachwiali się w swym zdecydowaniu, pojawił się czempion, spowity w błyskawice, władający piorunami, przez które wszystkim zjeżyły się włosy na głowie. Krzyknęliśmy wielkim głosem, gdy czempion opadł z nieba, wymierzając zdecydowaną sprawiedliwość ciosami swego elektrycznego dwuręcznego miecza. Każdy, kto tego dnia stanął do walki w naszej szlachetnej sprawie, przysiągł, że pewnego dnia będzie godny służyć ludowi jako czempion i wypełniać wolę sprawiedliwości”. – pilot paladyna-czempiona Danika Blaze, „RV-475888M: Dlaczego służymy”.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DIVINER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Diviner</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wróżbita</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="120"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DIVINER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Some consider me a diviner. That’s a false attribution. I’m just always running away. Diviners read ripples in the waves of chaos. They see invisible currents of inevitability. They perceive gaps, eddies and blurs in the flow of causality. What will, won’t or can’t be. I once met a true Diviner, but he could not perceive me at all. His friends had to assure him that I was not a prank. I figure I’ve always known I was good at avoiding fate. Maybe that’s my fate then: to have no fate.” – Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-00004300T: Oracles and Orioles”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Niektórzy uważają mnie za jasnowidza. Ale to błąd. Ja tylko zawsze uciekam. Za to jasnowidze czytają w zmarszczkach fal chaosu jak w otwartej książce. Dostrzegają niewidzialne prądy nieuchronności. Widzą luki, wiry i zamglenia w przepływie przyczynowości. Co się stanie, co nie, a co się stać nie może. Spotkałem raz prawdziwego jasnowidza, ale on nie mógł mnie dostrzec. Jego przyjaciele musieli go przekonywać, że nie jestem czyimś żartem. Zdaje się, że zawsze byłem dobry w uciekaniu przed przeznaczeniem. Może więc taki właśnie jest mój los – nie mieć przypisanego losu”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-00004300T: Wyrocznie i wydrzyki”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_EXEMPLAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Exemplar</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-ideał</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="135"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_EXEMPLAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Like a war god from legend, the mech rose to protect its subjects. The enemy encircled it, but with its shields extended the shots rang like rain upon a well-built rooftop. We thought perhaps that was it, until it shifted and struck an enemy artillery unit with its massive electrified glaive weapon. In a flash the towering titan shattered the enemy’s defenses, sending them spiraling in retreat. Clearly, the Oathbound Exemplar proves these newcomers will defend their ideals with more than just pleasing words.” – General Otis Falk, Horde Captain. “RV-422241M: Oathbound Force Assessments”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Mech podniósł się, by chronić swych podopiecznych, niczym legendarny bóg wojny. Nieprzyjaciele okrążyli go, ale dzięki osłonom ich kule tylko stukały niczym deszcz o solidnie zbudowany dach. Myśleliśmy, że to może już wszystko, gdy ideał skoczył i uderzył wrogie działo wielką elektryczną halabardą. W mgnieniu oka górujący nad otoczeniem tytan zdruzgotał umocnienia wroga i zmusił go do odwrotu. I tak ideał Nieugiętych pokazał, że przybysze będą bronić swoich idei czymś więcej niż tylko układnymi słowami”. – generał Otis Falk, dowódca hordy. „RV-422241M: Ocena sił Nieugiętych”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_WARLORD</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Warlord</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-dowódca</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_WARLORD</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"I’ve never been one for mechanized armored suits, even if they make you feel large and in charge. Just know that the Paladin Warlord’s Volt Surge is not a toy, but delivers arc energy to clusters of enemies. Also, those twin axes are not designed for living out lumberjack fantasies. The charged axes make trees explode, completely destroying the timber’s value. Not that I admit I ever tried that—Oathbound are very serious about whom they entrust with their equipment.” – Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-9110066T: Oracles and Orioles"</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Nigdy nie byłem zwolennikiem tych zmechanizowanych pancerzy bojowych, nawet jeśli dają one użytkownikowi poczucie wielkości i potęgi. Trzeba tylko wiedzieć, że udar elektryczny paladyńskiego dowódcy to nie igraszka, a narzędzie rażące piorunami całe bandy wrogów. Ten podwójny topór nie jest bynajmniej przeznaczony do zabawy w drwala. Naładowane elektrycznie ostrza sprawiają, że całe drzewa eksplodują, a to pozbawia drewno jakiejkolwiek wartości. Nie żebym sam tego próbował – Nieugięci bardzo poważnie podchodzą do udostępniania swego sprzętu obcym”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-9110066T: Wyrocznie i wydrzyki”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_MARQUIS</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Marquis</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-markiz</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Name (Paladin is a type of battlesuit)</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_MARQUIS</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"The inner animal lives by instinct. All flesh forgets vows. The Oathbound cannot make others virtuous. The way to Oathbound Honor is never forced. Virtue is a personal choice. We inspire the soul to change, aspiring to greater visions. Justice is not punishment. When Paladins mount their Marquis, fly their banners, and sound honor’s hymns, we all remember and regain our power. Ride on paladins to every low valley and upon every clime. Voyage until every ear hears the glorious news: we can free ourselves.” – Tedora Publia RV-453009E: The Paladin Poet"</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Wewnętrzne zwierzę kieruje się instynktem. Ciało zapomina o przysięgach. Nieugięci nie mogą uczynić innych cnotliwymi. Droga do honoru Nieugiętych nie może być wymuszona. Cnota to wybór osobisty. Zachęcamy dusze do zmian, budzimy pragnienie większej wizji. Sprawiedliwość to nie kara. Gdy paladyn wsiada do markiza, unosi swój sztandar i śpiewa hymn honoru, przypomina sobie i odzyskuje swoją moc. Paladyni potrafią przebyć każdą głęboką dolinę i wytrzymać każdy klimat. Idą niestrudzenie, aż każde ucho usłyszy wspaniałą wieść – możemy się uwolnić”. – Tedora Publia „RV-453009E: Paladyńska poetka”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Unit Description

The person of the quote is female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET_ARRIVAL</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOG</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">With guidance from your Seers, you must remain confident that you will not falter in your mission.[br/][br/]Battlesuits piloted by the elite and just Paladins under your command will inspire your people and strike fear in the minds of those that would threaten your kin. As Oathbound, you have enjoyed a perfect society in isolation, but now it is time to enlighten those who have fallen from grace in these savage times.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dzięki przewodnictwu naszych Wieszczów możesz zachować pewność tego, że wykonasz swoje zadanie.[br/][br/]Pancerze bojowe, pilotowane przez elitarnych, prawych paladynów pod twoim dowództwem natchną pozostałych żołnierzy i wzbudzą strach w umysłach tych, co zagrażają twoim pobratymcom. Jako Nieugięci cieszyliście się życiem w idealnym lecz odizolowanym społeczeństwie – nadeszła pora oświecenia innych, którzy w tych dzikich czasach utracili łaskę.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The person that speaks this is a Seer female</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_LIGHT_BRINGER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Light Bringer</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-światłodawca</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_PURIFIER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Purifier</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyn-czyściciel</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PALADIN_ECHO_WALKER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladin Echo Walker</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Paladyńskie echo</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BANNER_OF_PROTECTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Banner of Protection</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Sztandar ochrony</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BANNER_OF_PROTECTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"Assess Oathbound power anomaly. 
Observation: a single Oathbound Banner rallies their weak to strength. 
Q1: Does power reside in the cloth or the words emblazoned upon it? 
A1: Unknown. 
Q2: How does merely publicly displaying their standards transmit power? 
A2: Unknown. 
Q3: From whence does this prowess originate (or) counter inquiry: was it within them all along?
A3: Wasteful. Inefficient. Why not always use it? 
Risk Assessment: what if this power was replaced with inferior prosthetics during the Assembly subject creation process?
Mitigation: unknown.” – Assembly Threat Assessor, “RV-332876X: Inferiority Complex"</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Ocena anomalii mocy Nieugiętych. Obserwacja: jeden sztandar Nieugiętych przywraca siłę słabym. P1: Czy ta moc tkwi w płótnie, czy też w wyszytych na nim słowach? O1: Nie wiadomo. P2: W jaki sposób samo wzniesienie tego sztandaru przekazuje moc? O2: Nie wiadomo. P3: Skąd bierze się ta sprawność (lub) przeciwne pytanie – czy była w nich przez cały czas? O3: Marnotrawstwo. Niewydajność. Dlaczego nie używać jej zawsze? Ocena zagrożenia – co by było, gdyby zastąpić tę moc gorszą protezą podczas tworzenia osobnika Zgromadzenia? Złagodzenie – nieznane”. – taksator zagrożeń Zgromadzenia, „RV-332876X: Kompleks niższości”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">Structured like a question and answer list

The person of the quote is male</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><TopRowVisible>33</TopRowVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>44</ActiveRow><RangeSelection>R45</RangeSelection></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>