<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Frederick Milders</LastAuthor><LastSaved>2019-02-08T10:37:44Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>11175</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>25200</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:StyleID="s62" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="305.25"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="75.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="447.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="150"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="315"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="120.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="60"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENARIODEFINITIONS_HERITORCAMPAIGN</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="30"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MISSION_HERITOR01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">A liberated Indentured seeks to restore the name of his House.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wyzwolony ofiarny pragnie przywrócić cześć swojemu rodowi.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"House" as in Syndicate noble house.
Indentured is a Syndicate unit in the game.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Log in exile, entry 7321</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziennik wygnania, wpis 7321</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The bigger they are, the harder they fall. House Faron was once great among the Syndicate, respected by its rivals and feared by its enemies. Until the unthinkable happened, and my grandfather brought poverty and shame to our family. We were dispossessed, banned from business and our bloodline sold into slavery. I served our sentence as an Indentured soldier, fighting foreign wars until my freedom would be earned.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Im wyżej się wespniesz, tym boleśniej upadasz. Ród Faron należał kiedyś do wielkich klanów Syndykatu. Był szanowany przez swoich rywali i budził strach wśród wrogów. Aż stała się rzecz nie do pomyślenia i mój dziad przyniósł rodowi biedę i hańbę. Zostaliśmy wydziedziczeni, zakazano nam prowadzenia interesów i sprzedano w niewolę. Odsłużyłem swój wyrok jako żołnierz ofiarnych, walcząc w cudzych wojnach, aż zyskałem sobie wolność.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="6"><Data ss:Type="String">Im wyżej się wespniesz, tym boleśniej upadasz. Ród Faron należał kiedyś do wielkich klanów Syndykatu. Był szanowany przez swoich rywali i budził strach wśród wrogów. Aż stała się rzecz nie do pomyślenia i mój dziad przyniósł rodowi biedę i hańbę. Zostaliśmy wydziedziczeni, zakazano nam prowadzenia interesów i sprzedano w niewolę. Odsłużyłam swój wyrok jako żołnierz ofiarnych, walcząc w cudzych wojnach, aż zyskałam sobie wolność.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"House Faron" is the name of a Syndicate noble house.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Log in exile, entry 7337</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziennik wygnania, wpis 7337</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">In my misery, I’ve found the most unlikely of all companions: a re-enslaved Kir’Ko! Though his fate was worse than mine, Hatyl Es’Ran’s spirits were high and his will unbroken. He told me of the ancient Es’Teq, who had chosen him as their Prophet and could lead my family to redemption. At first, I laughed at him, but when he drained the very Essence from one of our Overseers, the situation changed. Together, we made our escape.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">W swoim nieszczęściu zdobyłem najbardziej niespodziewanego towarzysza – Kir’Ko uczynionego ponownie niewolnikiem! Choć jego los był gorszy niż mój, Hatyl Es’Ran nie upadł na duchu, a jego wola była niezłomna. Opowiedział mi o pradawnym Es’Tequ, który wybrał go na swego proroka i mógł odkupić przewiny mojego rodu. Najpierw wzbudziło to mój śmiech, ale gdy Hatyl przejął Esencję jednego z naszych nadzorców, sytuacja uległa zmianie. Wspólnie zdołaliśmy uciec.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="6"><Data ss:Type="String">W swoim nieszczęściu zdobyłam najbardziej niespodziewanego towarzysza – Kir’Ko uczynionego ponownie niewolnikiem! Choć jego los był gorszy niż mój, Hatyl Es’Ran nie upadł na duchu, a jego wola była niezłomna. Opowiedział mi o pradawnym Es’Tequ, który wybrał go na swego proroka i mógł odkupić przewiny mojego rodu. Najpierw wzbudziło to mój śmiech, ale gdy Hatyl przejął Esencję jednego z naszych nadzorców, sytuacja uległa zmianie. Wspólnie zdołaliśmy uciec.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"Hatyl Es'Ran" is the name of a male Kir'Ko character.
"Es'Teq" is the name of an ancient human theocratic dynasty.
"Prophet" is a title within the Es'Teq religion.
"Essence" is a term for life essence used by the Es'Teq. It is also present in inanimate objects, and machinery.
"Overseer" is the name of a Syndicate unit in the game.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Log in exile, entry 7339</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziennik wygnania, wpis 7339</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">My new ranks filled with liberated Indentured and exiles continue to grow. We are now on our way to Obolus-5, a planet once famous for its rich history and ruins. At least officially, but away from touristic attractions, adventurers and raiders from all across the Union followed the allure of the past and its secrets. According to Hatyl Es’Ran, this is where the Es’Teq went into hiding many millennia ago.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Szeregi mojej nowej armii, pełnej oswobodzonych ofiarnych i wygnańców, nieustannie się powiększały. Jesteśmy teraz w drodze na Obolusa-5, planetę słynącą niegdyś z interesującej historii i ruin. Przynajmniej oficjalnie, ale z dala od turystycznych atrakcji. Poszukiwacze przygód i łupieżcy z całego Związku szli za zewem przeszłości i jej tajemnic. Według Hatyla Es’Rana wiele tysiącleci temu właśnie tu skrył się Es’Teq.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"Obolus-5" is the name of a planet.
"Union" refers to the Star Union.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Log in exile, entry 7373</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziennik wygnania, wpis 7373</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="60"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obolus-5 is in visual range. I see why so many treasure hunters were once drawn here: the entire planet seems to breathe mystery. Despite all this, the Es’Teq have never been found. Sounds like unearthing their history will require more than some old-fashioned tomb-raiding…</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obolus-5 jest już w zasięgu obserwacji. Rozumiem, dlaczego niegdyś ściągało tu tylu poszukiwaczy skarbów. Cała planeta emanuje tajemniczością. Jednak pomimo wysiłków nie udało się odnaleźć Es’Tequ. Wygląda na to, że odkrycie jego historii będzie wymagało czegoś więcej niż staromodnego plądrowania grobowców…</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obolus-5</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Obolus-5</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_PLANETFALL_OBJECTIVE_01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">OBJECTIVES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Find the legacy of the Es'Teq</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Odszukaj dziedzictwo Es’Tequ</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Log in exile, entry 7581</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziennik wygnania, wpis 7581</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR01_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Opening the Regenesis Ark was an act of divine providence. As the beacon was lit its echoing signal spread to all Star Union worlds, releasing billions of Es’Teq minds from their ancient slumber. I, myself, became joined with their High Lord Xito Rhemenses. By accepting my role as Heritor Prophet, I will bring redemption not only to my own House, but to the sinners of other cultures and races alike.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Otwarcie Arki Regenezy było aktem bożej opatrzności. Gdy tylko zapalono sygnał, jego echa rozbiegły się po wszystkich światach Związku Gwiezdnego, wyzwalając miliardy umysłów Es’Tequ z pradawnej drzemki. Zostałem połączony z ich Najwyższym Władcą Xito Rhemensesem. Przyjąwszy rolę proroka Dziedziców, będę nieść odkupienie nie tylko własnemu rodowi, ale również grzesznikom z innych gatunków i cywilizacji.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="6"><Data ss:Type="String">Otwarcie Arki Regenezy było aktem bożej opatrzności. Gdy tylko zapalono sygnał, jego echa rozbiegły się po wszystkich światach Związku Gwiezdnego, wyzwalając miliardy umysłów Es’Tequ z pradawnej drzemki. Zostałam połączona z ich Najwyższym Władcą Xito Rhemensesem. Przyjąwszy rolę proroka Dziedziców, będę nieść odkupienie nie tylko własnemu rodowi, ale również grzesznikom z innych gatunków i cywilizacji.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"High Lord" is a religious title of the Es'Teq and the name of an Es'Teq unit in the game.
"Xito Rhemenses" is the name of a male human character.
"Regenesis Ark" is the name of an Es'Teq artifact.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">MISSION_HERITOR02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">On a Nexus Node gone dark, the Es'Teq face their old nemesis.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Węzeł Ogniwa gaśnie, a Es’Teq stawia czoła staremu wrogowi.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">For "Nexus Node" see the entry on the Nexus Network in the glossary.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litany of the Es'Teq, chapter 37 verse 28</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litania Es’Tequ, rozdział 37, werset 28</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Before Artok, the Creator, there was darkness in the universe. No matter or antimatter, only Entropy. But then Artok ignited the spark of creation, splitting his body into shards of Essence from which all life became born. We Es’Teq inherited his holy Essence, collecting and preserving it inside the pure until our God can be restored. Together we will build a paradise anchored in reality, where we ward off Entropy, and death is a stranger to all believers.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zanim nastał Artok Stworzyciel wszechświat ogarniała ciemność. Nie było materii ani antymaterii, jeno Entropia. Lecz wtedy Artok rozpalił iskrę tworzenia, rozszczepiając swe ciało na okruchy Esencji, z której narodziło się wszelkie życie. My, Es’Teq, dziedziczymy jego świętą Esencję, gromadząc ją i zachowując w czystych, aż będzie można odnowić naszego Boga. Wspólnie zbudujemy raj zakotwiczony w rzeczywistości, w którym ustrzeżemy się od Entropii, a śmierć będzie obca wszystkim wyznawcom.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"Artok" is the name of a male god that the Es'Teq believe in.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litany of the Es'Teq, chapter 37 verse 43</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litania Es’Tequ, rozdział 37, werset 43</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">But there are always those that blindly oppose divine rule. With the creation of artificial intelligence, the greatest sin against the sanctity of life was born. The mundane temptations of a virtual life corrupted the gullible masses, denying them any salvation within this reality. After their last holy war, the Es’Teq were forced to retreat. But now that Regenesis has occurred, the culling of AI can be resumed.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zawsze jednak znajdują się ślepi, którzy sprzeciwiają się bożej władzy. Stworzenie sztucznej inteligencji oznaczało narodziny największego z grzechów przeciwko świętości życia. Przyziemne pokusy wirtualnego żywota skaziły łatwowierne masy, uniemożliwiając im osiągnięcie zbawienia w tej rzeczywistości. Po ostatniej świętej wojnie Es’Teq został zmuszony do odwrotu. Ale skoro doszło do Regenezy, można podjąć na nowo trzebienie SI.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litany of the Es'Teq, chapter 37 verse 47</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litania Es’Tequ, rozdział 37, werset 47</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_BRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE03</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">All of this was revealed to me through my symbiont, Xito Rhemenses. He is guiding me to CNex Omega, the Union’s infamous center of cyber-crime, from where traffickers and Outlander rebels once launched most of their hacker attacks. After the Cataclysm, more ambitious forces took over the planet: there is word of a new master AI being created, another CORE to dominate us all! If this is true, I can only pray we arrive in time for a divine intervention.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wszystko to zostało mi objawione przez mego symbionta, Xito Rhemensesa. To on prowadzi mnie do CWO Omega, niesławnego ośrodka cyberprzestępczości Związku, z którego oszuści i buntownicy Zewnętrznych przypuszczali niegdyś większość swoich ataków hakerskich. Po Kataklizmie planetę przejęły ambitniejsze siły. Chodzą słuchy o powstaniu nowej głównej SI, nowego ŚWIAT-a, który zdominuje nas wszystkich! Jeśli to prawda, mogę się tylko modlić, abyśmy przybyli w porę na bożą interwencję.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"CNex Omega" is the name of a planet.
For "Outlander", "Cataclysm" and "CORE" see the respective entries in the glossary.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litany of the Es'Teq, chapter 37 verse 50</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litania Es’Tequ, rozdział 37, werset 50</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="45"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CNex Omega is engulfed in a red web of rogue satellites, greeting us with the looping transmissions of long-dead hackers. It is often said that even history keeps repeating itself. But not this time: We will purge the AI followers and their new CORE from this world!</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CWO Omega jest otoczony czerwoną siecią zbuntowanych satelitów, które witają nas zapętlonymi transmisjami przesłanymi przez od dawna martwych hakerów. Często się mówi, że historia lubi się powtarzać. Lecz nie tym razem – oczyścimy tę planetę ze zwolenników SI i ich nowego ŚWIAT-a!</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_PLANETFALL_DEFAULT</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">PLANET</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CNex Omega</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">CWO Omega</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_PLANETFALL_OBJECTIVE_01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">OBJECTIVES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Infiltrate CNex Omega with the Heritor technology</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zinfiltruj CWO Omega za pomocą technologii Dziedziców</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_PLANETFALL_OBJECTIVE_02</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">OBJECTIVES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Find and delete the new CORE AI</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Odszukaj i skasuj nową SI ŚWIAT-a</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litany of the Es'Teq, chapter 38 verse 1</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Litania Es’Tequ, rozdział 38, werset 1</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_DEBRIEFING_DEFAULT_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The sky shimmered like a heavenly dome as the Elevation Crystal started to breathe new circulating Essence into the veins of the Nexus Network. I was there, at the heart of the communion, listening to the voices of the faithful from all across the galaxy. Molded by the Es’Teq Conclave, their chant grew into an angelic chorus, ready to spread the words of salvation. Anyone touched by its lucent grace will either join in or perish.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Gdy Kryształ Uniesienia zaczął pompować nową Esencję w żyły sieci Ogniwo, niebo zajaśniało niczym niebiańska kopuła. Byłem tam, w sercu zespolenia, słuchając głosów wiernych z całej galaktyki. Ich śpiew, stopiony w jedno przez Konklawe Es’Tequ, stał się anielskim chórem, gotowym, by głosić słowo zbawienia. Każda istota tknięta jego świetlistą łaską albo uwierzy, albo zginie.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">"Elevation Crystal" is the name of an Es'Teq artifact.
"Es'Teq Conclave" is the name of a religious tribunal of the Es'Teq.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">HERITOR02_DEBRIEFING_REFORMATION_PAGE01</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">BRIEFING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">With the destruction of the Omega Server the followers of the AI and the Es’Teq have both been denied their weapon of mass conversion. No belief or doctrine should be forced upon anybody, but can only develop through reflection and gnosis. I have learned this from Hatyl Es’Ran, who has encouraged me to continue our reformation of the Es’Teq faith. Kir’Ko and Syndicate, host and symbiont – all can prosper as long as each mind retains its freedom.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Zniszczenie serwera Omega pozbawiło broni masowego nawracania zarówno Es’Teq, jak i zwolenników SI. Żadna wiara ani doktryna nie będzie już nikomu narzucana – zamiast tego będą się rozwijać dzięki refleksji i poznaniu. Nauczyłem się tego od Hatyla Es’Rana, który zachęcił mnie do kontynuowania naszej reformy religii Es’Tequ. Kir’Ko i Syndykat, nosiciel i symbiont – wszyscy mogą rozkwitać, dopóki umysły pozostają wolne.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="6"><Data ss:Type="String">Zniszczenie serwera Omega pozbawiło broni masowego nawracania zarówno Es’Teq, jak i zwolenników SI. Żadna wiara ani doktryna nie będzie już nikomu narzucana – zamiast tego będą się rozwijać dzięki refleksji i poznaniu. Nauczyłam się tego od Hatyla Es’Rana, który zachęcił mnie do kontynuowania naszej reformy religii Es’Tequ. Kir’Ko i Syndykat, nosiciel i symbiont – wszyscy mogą rozkwitać, dopóki umysły pozostają wolne.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"Omega Server" is the name of a Synthesis server build on CNex Omega.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VO: Male Syndicate or Female Syndicate</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7"><Data ss:Type="String">General Loca Notes for this XML: For references to game terminology and in-world references, please check the glossary delivered as part of the documentation.

In the text below, text is spoken by a character who can be either male or female (except for Amazon, which is always female). If relevant for translation, please use the ‘localized string’ column for the male text and the ‘alternative localized string’ column for the female text.</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String"/></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Zoom>130</Zoom><Selected/><TopRowVisible>15</TopRowVisible><LeftColumnVisible>2</LeftColumnVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>29</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>2</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>