<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:53Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-25T00:04:57Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>5640</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>15345</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultRowHeight="14.4375"><Column ss:Width="94.5"/><Column ss:Width="84.75"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:Width="529.5"/><Column ss:Width="144.75"/><Column ss:Width="191.25"/><Column ss:Width="117.75"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="86.4375"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_ARTIFICIAL</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Malware Daemon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Demon wirusowy</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The program continued to gather resources in the area. At first, there was no physical manifestation of the Malware Daemon, but soon a small holographic projector lifted and another flickered on and a small web of yellow light danced between them. A blue arc of electricity crackled from an improvised electrical arc buzzer. It darted across the line of automated defenses and stopped before attempting to transmit its consciousness. The gate swung open and the turret turned on the guards just inside the gate. We now had access to the complex.”— Haxor Jaxor, “RV-45003C: Your code-sharks have no bytes”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Program nadal zbierał zasoby w okolicy. Początkowo demon wirusowy nie wytworzył żadnej fizycznej manifestacji, ale wkrótce uniósł się mały projektor holograficzny, potem zamigotał inny, a między nimi zatańczyła siateczka żółtego światła. Z zaimprowizowanego brzęczyka wystrzelił błękitny łuk wyładowania elektrycznego. Przebił się przez linię automatycznej obrony i zatrzymał się, po czym spróbował przesłać jego świadomość. Brama rozwarła się na oścież, a wieżyczka zwróciła się przeciwko pobliskim strażnikom. Uzyskaliśmy dostęp do kompleksu”. – Haxor Jaxor, „RV-45003C – Wasi mistrzowie kodowania nie mają bajtów”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1B</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Reconstructed Daemon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Demon zrekonstruowany</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="28.6875"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER1B</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">The Reconstructed Daemon is a small robotic automation with a Daemon inside, controlling it. Due to being built from the remains of a dead unit, the construction is flimsy.</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Demon zrekonstruowany jest małym robotem mieszczącym w sobie demona, który nim steruje. Powstał ze szczątków zniszczonej jednostki, przez co jego budowa nie jest zbyt solidna.</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: Constructed -&gt; Due to being built</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Hacker</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Haker</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2A</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The Hacker said she fought for ultimate freedom. Apparently, that involves replacing your face with a virtual one. If she gets tired of her face, she searches a book of faces, replacing older models with newer models. She said Hackers eventually replace everything. She used implants to quicken her neural link to her network. Hackers achieve ultimate freedom by deploying code-constructs called Daemons to protect themselves and override conformist programming. The ultimate goal of the Synthesis is to achieve perfect mastery over all virtual worlds. That said, I think I’m happy with my boring face.”— Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-5580X: Forgotten Places”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Hakerka twierdziła, że walczy o najwyższy wymiar wolności. Najwyraźniej wolność taka wiąże się z wymianą prawdziwej twarzy na wirtualną. Gdy jej oblicze zaczyna ją nużyć, przeszukuje katalog twarzy i wymienia stare modele na nowe. Powiedziała, że ostatecznie hakerzy wymienią wszystko. Stosowała implanty do przyspieszenia łącza neuronalnego z siecią. Najwyższą wolność hakerzy osiągną, generując twory kodowe zwane demonami, które będą ich chronić i przebudowywać konformistyczne oprogramowanie. Ostatecznym celem Syntezy będzie osiągnięcie doskonałego opanowania wszystkich światów wirtualnych. Mimo wszystko ja jestem całkiem zadowolony z mojej nudnej twarzy”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-5580X – Zapomniane miejsca”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Edit: removed extra space after "Synthesis"</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2B</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Network Link</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Łącze sieciowe</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER2B</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The Synthesis know that it’s basic military strategy to disrupt the enemy’s lines of communication. That’s why the more adept members never attack without the support of a mobile network node called a "Modified Type-A Network Link." If they turn our machinery against us, focus the assault on the link. Be careful, the link is protected with a gun turret. The link can reset the internal safety protocols of weaponry under its control. Synthesis Daemons are enhanced by the link as well, enabling them to shrug off counter-measures.”— Major Sherwood Gordon, “RV-30400M: Cyberwarfare”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Synteza rozumie, że podstawową strategią wojskową jest zakłócenie łączności wroga. Właśnie dlatego zdolniejsi członkowie organizacji nigdy nie atakują bez wsparcia ruchomego węzła sieci zwanego «zmodyfikowanym łączem sieciowym typu A». Jeśli zwrócą nasze maszyny przeciwko nam, skup się na atakowaniu łącza, ale zachowaj ostrożność, gdyż jest ono chronione przez wieżyczkę karabinową. Łącze może resetować wewnętrzne protokoły bezpieczeństwa kontrolowanego uzbrojenia. Wzmacnia też demony Syntezy, dzięki czemu są one w stanie przezwyciężyć środki zaradcze”. – major Sherwood Gordon, „RV-30400M – Cyberwojna”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Avatar</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Awatar</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">TIER3</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“An assortment of machines followed the radiant face *[dongle*]. Propelled by their own motion servos, gesticulating limbs, drones, mech and *[deadly pound cakes*], the machines swarmed around *[General Moron*]. I tried to approach but my vehicle had already been compromised by the Avatar’s disruption viruses *[and my ugly face*]. None of the machines in the force appeared to be functioning to capacity, while the machines hijacked by the Synthesis activists gathered, awaiting the command *[to eat all the idiot-pills*]. I ordered my troops to *[wet themselves*].”— General *[Butt-Head Jerkface*], “RV-00000M: L33T Hackers 43V3r!*[System Record Compromised*]”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s62"><Data ss:Type="String">„Cała gromada maszyn podążała za świetlistą twarzą *[dongle*]. Napędzane serwomotorami ruchowymi, gestykulujące kończy, drony, mechy i *[deadly pound cakes*] zaroiły się wokół *[General Moron*]. Próbowałem się zbliżyć, ale mój pojazd był już unieruchomiony przez awatara za pomocą jego wirusów zakłócających *[and my ugly face*]. Żadne z urządzeń naszego oddziału nie funkcjonowało prawidłowo, a maszyny opanowane przez aktywistów Syntezy gromadziły się, oczekując na rozkazy *[to eat all the idiot-pills*]. Nakazałem moim żołnierzom, by *[wet themselves*]” – generał *[Butt-Head Jerkface*], „RV-00000M – L33T Hackers 43V3r!*[System Record Compromised*]”</Data></Cell><Cell ss:Index="8"><Data ss:Type="String">Changed '[]' into '*[*]' where the '[]' were intended to be displayed to the player - i.e. where it doesn't concern markup text.
We need to be sure to change this in the localized text too, as this change was made after the text was send out for localization.
Please remove this comment when the changes are made, but only after verifying this was done for all languages supported at launch.</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><TopRowVisible>4</TopRowVisible><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>11</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>2</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>