<?xml version="1.0"?><?mso-application progid="Excel.Sheet"?><Workbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:x="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel" xmlns:ss="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40"><DocumentProperties xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><LastAuthor>Djurre van Dijk</LastAuthor><Created>2019-05-06T09:39:59Z</Created><LastSaved>2019-05-06T09:39:59Z</LastSaved><Version>16.00</Version></DocumentProperties><OfficeDocumentSettings xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office"><AllowPNG/></OfficeDocumentSettings><ExcelWorkbook xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><WindowHeight>7620</WindowHeight><WindowWidth>21570</WindowWidth><WindowTopX>32767</WindowTopX><WindowTopY>32767</WindowTopY><RefModeR1C1/><ProtectStructure>False</ProtectStructure><ProtectWindows>False</ProtectWindows></ExcelWorkbook><Styles><Style ss:ID="Default" ss:Name="Normal"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom"/><Borders/><Font ss:FontName="Calibri" x:Family="Swiss" ss:Size="11" ss:Color="#000000"/><Interior/><NumberFormat/><Protection/></Style><Style ss:ID="s62"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Bottom" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s63"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top"/></Style><Style ss:ID="s64"><Alignment ss:Vertical="Top" ss:WrapText="1"/></Style></Styles><Worksheet ss:Name="Script"><Table x:FullColumns="1" x:FullRows="1" ss:DefaultColumnWidth="9" ss:DefaultRowHeight="15"><Column ss:Width="106.5"/><Column ss:Width="102"/><Column ss:StyleID="s62" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="605.25" ss:Span="1"/><Column ss:Index="5" ss:AutoFitWidth="0" ss:Width="147" ss:Span="3"/><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="135"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SPECIES_WILDLIFE</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"/><Cell ss:Index="7" ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">The DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES column contains info on what text between { } signs means (if applicable). It usually stands for either a numeric value, or a numeric value with an icon. Text between [ ] signs stands for a certain type of icon. </Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"/></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">SCENE ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">TEXT ID</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s64"><Data ss:Type="String">ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE ENGLISH STRING</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">ALTERNATIVE LOCALIZED STRING</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">LOCALIZATION NOTES</Data></Cell><Cell ss:StyleID="s63"><Data ss:Type="String">DEV TEAM / MISC NOTES</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_SHRIKE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wild Shrike</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dzika dzierzba</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_SHRIKE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Story goes: Star Union planets were overrun with interstellar vermin known as Space Pigeons. A real menace. They consumed whole fields of crops. Their filthy droppings covered every surface. Terratech tried fixing the matter. They discover a planet with no Space Pigeons. This planet has a natural predator of the vermin. So Terratech enters the Shrike into their Genetic Ark as a “natural remedy” to the Space Pigeon without testing the results at scale. It’s wildly successful. Too successful. Sure, the crops are safe, but you ever been hit by Shrike droppings?”—Kelly Angel, Satirist, “RV-3411E: Genetic Jokes”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Było tak: planety Związku Gwiezdnego zostały opanowane przez międzygwiezdne szkodniki znane jako kosmiczne gołębie. Było to prawdziwe utrapienie. Ptactwo pożerało plony prosto z pól, a jego plugawe ekskrementy pokryły wszystko. Terratech próbował znaleźć rozwiązanie. Odkrył planetę bez kosmicznych gołębi, którą zamieszkiwał naturalny wróg tych szkodników. I tak oto Terratech wprowadził dzierzbę do swojej arki genetycznej jako «naturalne rozwiązanie» problemu kosmicznych gołębi bez badania skutków takiego działania na większą skalę. Sukces był ogromny. Zbyt ogromny. Oczywiście plony są znów bezpieczne, ale mieliście kiedyś wątpliwą przyjemność oberwać odchodami dzierzby?” – satyryczka Kelly Angel, „RV-3411E – Dowcipy genetyczne”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_SWIFT_BEAK</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wild Swift Beak</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziki chyżodziób</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="105"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_SWIFT_BEAK</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Across the forested expanse of Terra-III they gallop. Majestic are the Swift Beak herds. Come and see these creatures in their natural habitat. Though not technically a beak, these creatures use their thick sharpened chin horn to strike at threats. Never fear, we guarantee your safety! Let our experienced ranchers domesticate your pick of the herd in our all-expenses-paid ‘Swift Beak Rancher Experience Vacation Pack.’ Stay in our luxury suites, eat rustic meals with real ranchers, and go home with your very own Swift Beak steed.”—Unknown, Adworxs Agency Archive, “RV-93A: Terra-III Tourism Account”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Galopują poprzez leśne połacie Terra-III. Stada chyżodziobów są doprawdy majestatyczne. Przybądźcie tu, by ujrzeć te stworzenia w ich naturalnym środowisku. Tak właściwie nie mają one dziobów – atakują za pomocą grubych, zaostrzonych rogów, jakie wyrastają im z podbródków. Ale bez obaw, gwarantujemy wam bezpieczeństwo! Nasi doświadczeni ranczerzy oswoją wybrane przez was stado w ramach pakietu all-inclusive «Wakacje Łowcy Chyżodziobów». Będziecie mieszkać w luksusowych apartamentach, delektować się rustykalnymi potrawami w towarzystwie prawdziwych ranczerów, a do domu powieziecie własnego chyżodzioba przysposobionego pod wierzch” – anonim, archiwum Agencji Adworxs, „RV-93A – Reklama turystyczna Terra-III”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_HARRIER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wild Harrier</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziki błotniak</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_HARRIER</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Um, yes? Hello? Is this animal control? I’m calling on behalf of my neighbor, Zeb. There’s a large bat-dragon on his rooftop. Yeah, hostile. It ate his dog. It’s breaking through his roof. Oh dear. I think that’s his wife, Marlene, in its jaws. Yes, A Harrier? I don’t care what it’s called. Can’t you kill it? I don’t care if it’s endangered, it’s eating my neighbor’s wife. There goes Zeb. Sorry Zeb, I can’t get the door, I’m on the phone. Look at the thing fly! It’s swooping! Oh dear…  It’s eating Zeb.”—Narda Melifu, “RV-0224E: Colony Laugh-a-long”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Halo? Czy to służby zoologiczne? Dzwonię w imieniu sąsiada, Zeba. Na dachu jego domu siedzi jakiś wielki smok-nietoperz. Owszem, nieprzyjazny. Zeżarł mu psa. A teraz wyłamuje dach. O rany. Chyba widziałem w jego paszczy żonę Zeba, Marlenkę. Tak. Błotniak? A co mnie obchodzi, jak to się nazywa? Nie możecie go zabić? Co z tego, że to zagrożony gatunek, przecież pożera sąsiadowi żonę. O, idzie Zeb. Przepraszam cię, Zeb, nie mogę podejść do drzwi, rozmawiam przez telefon. Ależ ten stwór śmiga! Leci tuż nad ziemią! O rany... Teraz wcina Zeba” – Narda Melifu, „RV-0224E – Kabaret kolonialny Śmiech na Zdrowie”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_BOMBARDON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wild Bombardon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dziki bombardon</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="75"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">WILD_BOMBARDON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“The Bombardon cautiously eyed Ranger Craig. Swollen glands on either side of its neck throbbed. Green sludge oozed from its frog-like maw. Ranger Craig steadied his voice and said, “Easy, big fellow… PharmaCorp pays good money for monster snot. I just want a sample.” The creature let out a guttural croak and suddenly a glob of goo erupted from the Bombardon’s mouth, covering the Ranger.  When PharmaCorp drones retrieved Ranger Craig’s remains, they had more than enough Bombardon sample for their need.”—Ranger S. P. Rocket, “RV-549S: Wildlife Protection Course”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Bombardon uważnie zmierzył strażnika Craiga wzrokiem. Napęczniałe gruczoły pulsowały mu po obu stronach karku. Z ropuszej paszczy ściekał zielony śluz. Strażnik Craig odezwał się opanowanym głosem: «Spokojnie, kolego... PharmaCorp świetnie płaci za gluty potwora. Potrzebuję tylko próbki». Stwór wydał z siebie gardłowy skrzek i nagle z paszczy bombardona wystrzeliła kula mazi, pokrywając strażnika od stóp do głów. Gdy drony PharmaCorpu odnalazły szczątki strażnika Craiga, zdobyły aż nadto próbek śluzu bombardona” – strażnik leśny S.P. Rocket, „RV-549S – Kurs ochrony przyrody”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VORADON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Voradon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Głododon</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0" ss:Height="90"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">VORADON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">“Geneticaworld Themepark was supposed to make Terratech a boatload of money. Bragging about their creations, the CEO assured his guests nothing could go wrong. I remember his shrieks when a Kir'Ko Ravenous/Tyrannadon hybrid escaped its containment. The Voradon’s wounds healed with each lawyer, animal handler and infantryman it devoured. I escaped on a child’s hoverboard. Voradons overran the countryside, leading the Star Union eventually to quarantine the planet. Now and then, some military genius will capture a Voradon, thinking to exploit its savage power. The story always ends with blood splatters and screaming.” —Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-2220X: Runaway!”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Park rozrywki Genetica miał zarabiać dla Terratechu mnóstwo forsy. Chwaląc się fantastycznymi wynalazkami, prezes zapewniał gości, że nic nie ma prawa się popsuć. Pamiętam jego wrzaski, gdy uciekła im hybryda wygłodniałego Kir'Ko i tyranodona. Rany głododona zasklepiały się wraz z każdym pożartym prawnikiem, treserem i żołnierzem. Uciekłem na dziecięcej poduszkorolce. Głododony opanowały okolicę, zmuszając w końcu Związek Gwiezdny do odizolowania całej planety. Od czasu do czasu jakiś geniusz wojskowy łapie głododona i myśli, że wykorzysta jego nieokiełznaną moc. W finale każdej takiej historii występują wrzaski i bryzgająca krew”. – Mah Reg'Nib, „RV-2220X – Uciekać!”</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RACE</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME_SINGULAR</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wildlife</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Dzika przyroda</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RAGING_TYRANODON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">NAME</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Savage Tyrannodon</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">Wściekły tyranodon</Data></Cell></Row><Row ss:AutoFitHeight="0"><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">RAGING_TYRANODON</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">DESCRIPTION</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">"I remember that Sheila was a screamer. I get it. It’s instinct to panic when a Savage Tyrannodon roars right behind you. When I panic, I hide, cower, and maybe soil myself. It’s far superior to what Sheila did. It’s just a really bad idea to run screaming into a clearing where the massive predator can easily crush you with its heavy tail before gulping you down in one brutal snap of its massive jaws. I think I’d eat her too, just to stop all that noise she was making.” – Mah Reg’Nib, “RV-38429T: Surviving Deadly Wildlife Encounters”</Data></Cell><Cell><Data ss:Type="String">„Pamiętam, że Sheila lubiła wrzeszczeć. Rozumiem to. Gdy słyszysz tuż za sobą ryk wściekłego tyranodona, wpadasz w panikę całkowicie instynktownie. No ale gdy ja wpadam w panikę, ukrywam się, kulę, może nurzam w błocie. Błoto jest dużo lepsze niż to, co zrobiła Sheila. Nie jest dobrym pomysłem uciekać z wrzaskiem leśną przecinką, w której ten ogromny drapieżca może cię z łatwością zmiażdżyć ogonem na papkę, a potem pochłonąć jednym kłapnięciem swoich mocarnych szczęk. W sumie chyba sam bym ją zeżarł, po prostu aby ucichł już ten jej przenikliwy wrzask”. – Mah Reg’Nib, „RV-38429T – Jak przetrwać spotkanie ze śmiercionośną dziką przyrodą”</Data></Cell></Row></Table><WorksheetOptions xmlns="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:excel"><Unsynced/><Print><ValidPrinterInfo/><HorizontalResolution>600</HorizontalResolution><VerticalResolution>600</VerticalResolution></Print><Selected/><Panes><Pane><Number>3</Number><ActiveRow>12</ActiveRow><ActiveCol>3</ActiveCol></Pane></Panes><ProtectObjects>False</ProtectObjects><ProtectScenarios>False</ProtectScenarios></WorksheetOptions></Worksheet></Workbook>